train wig ride
trainかつらの乗り隨が
Academia Sinica's August knowledge test lecture begins
中央研究院8月份知識想驗演講會開始
We ask Vice President Liu Dong to host for us
我們請劉副東副院長為我們主持
It is an honor and a pleasure to introduce the multi-institute Institute of Biomedical Sciences
很榮幸很高興介紹多研究院的生物醫學科學研究所
Also my colleague Tao Minghua researcher
也是我的所的同事陶明華研究員
Dr. Tao graduated from the first-level department of National Taiwan University
陶博士是在臺大一級系畢業之後
He went to study in America
他到美國留學
Bea University at the Top Individual
在頂尖的個人比亞大學
Get a Ph.D. in Immunology and Microbiology
拿到博士學位是在免疫跟微生物的博士學位
Then he went to another top university
之後他到另外一個頂尖大學
Postdoctoral Research at Stanford University in California
史丹佛大學在加州的博士後的研究
where the main research is related to the total flow
在那裡主要的研究是在跟總流有關
After that, he returned to Taiwan to enter the Academia Sinica
之後他回臺灣進入中研院
From assistant researcher to associate researcher to researcher very smoothly
很順利的從助研究員到副研究員到研究員
Now a researcher at the Institute of Biomedical Sciences
現在是生醫所的研究員
His research work has always been related to total flow
他的研究工作一直跟總流有關
This year is gene therapy or immunotherapy
今年是在基因的治療或是免疫治療
It's also his topic today
也是他今天的主題
In this regard, he has made many contacts and contributions.
這方面他有很多接觸的貢獻
also published in good journals
也是發表在很好的期刊
He also received many awards
他也拿到不少的獎項
including hospital
包括中醫院的
Here are the many awards for young scholars
這是年輕學者諸多獎
and the Ministry of Science and Technology
還有科技部的
Contact Research Award
接觸研究獎
Immunotherapy has been
免疫療法是過去一直受到
Attention in Oncology World
在腫瘤世界的關注
Some breakthroughs in recent years
最近幾年來有些突破
And it's a very exciting breakthrough
而且是讓人家非常興奮的突破
In fact I was about a year ago
事實上我在一年前左右
I also give a talk on immuno-oncology
我也給個演講跟免疫腫瘤
immune therapy
免疫的療法有關
I recognize the title after
我認得之後的題目是
Immunotherapy sees light
免疫療法建署光
But in fact it's not just sign light
但事實上是不只是署光而已
It should be fairly obvious by now
現在應該是相當明顯的
Very excited, Dr. Tao has his expertise in this area and the results of his research
非常興奮的 陶博士在這方面有他的專長跟他的研究上面的成果
So I believe he will give us a very incisive and wonderful speech today
所以我相信他今天會給我們非常精闢精彩的一個演講
We welcome Dr. Tao with warm applause
我們是熱烈掌聲 歡迎陶博士
Hello everyone Man An
大家好 滿安
Today is more tense than in the international lecture hall
今天比在國際的演講場還緊張
Because in Chinese, the task we received was to put all the slides in Chinese
因為用中文我們接到的任務就是把所有的幻燈片全部中文化
Then the speeches all use Chinese nouns
然後演講全部都是用中文的名詞
This is a big challenge for our researchers at Academia Sinica
這個對我們中研院的研究員來講是一個很大的挑戰
So actually these slides for this talk took quite a while to make
所以其實這個演講這些投影片花了相當多時間來製作
I hope to be able to use some relatively easy-to-understand scientific language
希望能夠用一些比較淺顯易懂的科學的語言
then communicate with everyone
然後跟大家溝通
Currently this rather promising approach to cancer treatment
目前這個相當有前景的癌症治療的方法
Then I will try to introduce to you today what is immunotherapy
那我今天會嘗試跟大家介紹什麼叫免疫治療
In fact, immunotherapy
其實免疫治療
Or our simplest is this
還是我們最簡單的就是這樣
Does everyone in English understand this?
這個英文的大家懂不懂
using the body to fight cancer
using the body to fight cancer
with your own body
用你自己的身體
to fight cancer
去跟癌症對抗
In fact, against these tumors against cancer
其實對抗這些腫瘤對抗癌症
These key weapons are needed
所需要的這些關鍵的武器
we all have
我們身體都有
just because of different genetic background
只是因為不同的基因背景
some people his immune system
有些人他的免疫系統
Easier and more effective against cancer
比較容易有效的對付癌症
some people are worse
有一些人就比較差
Now in immunotherapy
那現在在免疫治療
I just hope to use some foreign medicine
就是希望能夠用一些外來的藥物
Overcome stimulates the patient's immune system
克服激發病人的免疫系統
to fight cancer
來對付癌症
This is Cancer Immunotherapy
這就是癌症的免疫治療
has been going on for quite a long time
已經持續相當長的時間
Then I will start today
那我今天就會從
Because we are in a hurry
因為我們時間比較匆忙一點
I will learn from his past
我會從他的研究的過去
In fact, there have been more than 100 years of research history in the past
過去其實已經超過100年的研究歷史
The current situation is what Vice President Liu just said
現況就剛剛我們劉副所講的
Most recently this has been around since 2010
最近這大概從2010年開始之後
a big breakthrough of
的一個很大的突破
Also see very good prospects in patients
在病人也看到非常好的前景
but only just started
但是才剛剛開始
the future means
那未來就是說
how do we go from here
我們怎麼樣從現在的基礎之上
Can have a bigger breakthrough
再能夠有更大的突破
can bring more patients
能夠造會更多的病人
Then this is the mission of our Academia Sinica Research Institute
那這個就是我們中研研究院的使命
Because we're not on the front lines caring for clinical patients
因為我們不在第一線照顧臨床病人
This is the job of the clinician
這個是臨床醫師的職任
But all we have to do is
但是我們要做的就是
How can medical
怎麼樣能夠解決醫學上
Problems that have not yet been resolved
現在還沒有辦法解決的問題
These results can then be
然後再將這些成果能夠
Transfer to clinic for treatment
轉移到臨床去做治療
Then this is the expectation of our Academia Sinica
那這個就是我們中研院的期許
It is also our responsibility now
也是我們現在的責任
then i will today
那我今天就
From here, the more detailed content
從這邊開始,那比較詳細的一些內容
Actually, last month, our weekly report in Zhongyuan Hospital
我其實在上個月吧,我們在中原醫院的週報
I also wrote on the same topic, and also wrote all his Chinese
也寫了就同樣的題目,也是把他全部中文化
And I found a colleague, he is an editor, so he can understand
而且我找了一個同事,他是編輯,所以他看得懂
So I believe it will be easier for everyone to understand
所以我相信就是會更容易讓大家可以理解
What about everyone, there will be some lectures on the sidelines, and it will be on the Internet
那大家呢,所邊會有一些講音,那在網路上面
You can also extract his PDF file
也可以去將他的PDF檔給摘錄下來
Then my entire speech today will probably focus on this content.
那我今天的整個的演講大概是以這個內容為主
Plus some new developments
再加上一些新的進展
Then, let yourself vent first, lest you get too late
然後,首先先自洩,免得到時候來不及
So in our lab, today I'm going to have a short, last short
所以我們實驗室,今天我會有一小段,最後一小段
Let’s talk about our voice first, then the results, which is the Zhongyuan Hospital just mentioned
講我們先聲音就成果,就是剛剛講的中原醫院
That is, we need to make some breakthroughs on the basis of existing
就是我們需要在現有的基礎之上再做一些突破
Let's use some animal models to see
我們用一些動物的模式去看
Uh, how can immunotherapy go a step further, uh, to improve the effect of lung transformation?
呃 免疫治療 怎麼樣能夠更進一步的 呃 化肺大效果
Then this is my postdoctoral researcher Dr. Jiaren Wu
那這就是我博士後研究員吳嘉仁博士
And the lab assistant, uh
還有實驗室的呃 助理哦
He used to be National Taiwan University, uh, Vincent & Associates
他過去是台大 呃 文生務所
Graduating master's students
畢業的碩士班學生
Yes, Cai Yiting
嗯 蔡議庭
oh their work
哦 他們的工作
What about the other thing? Today’s slides are all in Chinese.
那另外呢 今天的這個 所有的投影片呢 全部中文化
that includes some animation
那 包括一些動畫
Then invite us to this one
那請我們 這一所哦
Mr. Zhang Fengbi from the art room, Mr. Zhang Zimin, assisted
的美工室的張峰畢先生 張子民先生 協助
come on make these slides
來 來 製作這些幻燈片
ok first sentence
好 首先第一句
This may scare many people
這個可能很多人會嚇到
Everyone has cancer cells in their bodies, including the current
每個人身體內都有癌細胞 包括現在的
In fact, of course I can't say so, uh, sure
其實我當然沒有辦法講的那麼的 呃 肯定
But from the evidence of many animal experiments, I will show you the evidence later
但是從很多的動物實驗的證據 等一下我要給大家看這些證據
Maybe we all have cancer cells in our bodies
可能我們身體都有癌細胞
good
好
So why are most of us still cancer-free?
那為什麼我們大部分還是沒得癌症
that's because we
那因為我們
no immune system
沒有免疫系統
help you in
幫你在
overcome
克服
against these cancer cells
在對付這些癌細胞
then let me first introduce
那我首先先介紹一下
Cancers that are common in Taiwan and the world
台灣常見跟世界常見的癌症
this is 104 years
這是104年
Cancer Ranking in Taiwan
台灣地區的癌症排名
In fact, almost none of these have changed.
其實這幾個幾乎都沒有變過
Lung cancer in the first three years
前三年就是肺癌
Liver cancer Muscle intestine Spinal bowel
肝癌 肌腸 脊腸
Fatty bowel, liver cancer, colorectal cancer
脂腸 肝癌這個大腸癌
Look at the world ranking
你看全世界的排名
he
他
The top few are lung cancer, brain cancer and colorectal cancer
最高的前幾名就是肺癌 腦癌 跟大腸癌
So your brain cancer ranks fourth in Taiwan
所以你性的腦癌在台灣是第四位
But it is second in the world
但是在全世界是第二位
highest death rate
死亡率最高的
The highest death rate is lung cancer
死亡率最高是肺癌
Then came liver cancer, then colon cancer
然後接來是肝癌 再次是大腸癌
So this is our common
所以這是我們常見的
Right now it's been going on for 20+ years
就現在 這已經維持了20幾年
Cancer is the first of the top ten experiments
癌症都是十大實驗的第一位
So the shape of human disease will actually change
所以人類的疾病形態其實會改變
related to our medical technology
跟我們的醫療的技術有關係
I'll show you guys later
等一下會給大家看一下
is how medical technology
就是怎麼樣醫療技術
How to change the shape of our disease
怎麼樣去改變我們疾病的形態
Now everyone is most afraid of cancer
現在大家最怕是癌症
but 50 years ago
可是在50年前
Everyone is most afraid that it is not cancer
大家最怕不是癌症
is another disease
是別的疾病
many infectious diseases
很多傳染病
Another point is the treatment of cancer
另外有一點要在癌症的治療上面
The most effective cancer treatment available now
現在最有效的癌症治療
should be detected early
應該是早期發現
if you catch cancer early
你如果早期發現癌症
no matter what treatment
不管用什麼樣治療
its cure rate
它的治癒率
are very high
都非常的高
For example, take this example
比如說以這個例子來講
this colorectal cancer
這個大腸癌
colorectal cancer
大腸癌
colorectal cancer in this place
大腸癌在這個地方
Original colorectal cancer
原味大腸癌
when you find out
當你發現的時候
If it belongs to the early
如果是屬於早期的
Doctors have many ways to control
醫生就有很多方法可以控制
Surgical disaster was probably the first
手術災促大概是第一個
In addition, you can use local radiation therapy
另外你可以用局部的放射治療
But if this IC package spreads
可是如果這個IC包擴散
Diffusion is about leaving this original position
擴散就是要離開這個原位的位置
Transfer to Hall 08 Vascular
轉移到08館血管
For example, in this case it will go through this dry portal vein
比如說這個例子它會透過這個乾門靜脈
The dry portal vein is where our intestines
乾門靜脈是存在我們腸道
a very important source of blood supply
一個很重要的血液供應的來源
With this dry portal vein
隨著這乾門靜脈
The IC package will spread to the first station
IC包就會擴散到第一站
just do it
就是乾
Many colorectal cancer patients
很多大腸癌的病人
may exceed 50%
可能超過50%
after diagnosis
在診斷之後
dry transfer
當時就發現有乾轉移
25%
25%
Another 45% were found to have dry metastases after treatment
另外有45%是治療之後才發現有乾轉移
So if we can detect early
所以如果能夠在提早發現
before dry transfer
在乾轉移之前
able to treat patients of this size
能夠去治療這大小的病人
Colorectal cancer has a very high cure rate
大腸癌跡治愈率非常的高的
What's more
那另外呢就是
This is it
就是這個
metastatic cancer
就是轉移癌
In fact, it is the biggest difficulty in our treatment.
其實才是我們現在治療上面最大的困難
Once the cancer has metastasized
一旦癌症已經轉移了
In fact, we have very few weapons at our disposal.
其實我們可以用的武器都非常少
chemotherapy
化療
Still the first-line drug
還是第一線的用藥
additional targeted therapy
另外的標靶治療
But these are very difficult
但是這些呢都很困難去
completely cured
完全治愈
The patient with metastatic cancer
這個轉移癌的病人
Immunotherapy until now
一直到現在的免疫治療
start to see
開始可以看到
seems to be ok
好像可以Q
it can be cured
就可以治好
Metastatic cancer in the past
過去已經轉移癌
You rarely use a term like cure
你其實很少用治好這樣子的名詞
Most of the past
大部分過去都是講
years of survival
幾年的存活率
one year survival rate
一年存活率
three-year survival rate
三年存活率
five-year survival rate
五年存活率
rarely cured
很少用治好的
so now we can start talking slowly
那現在我們可以開始慢慢講
It seems that some patients
好像有些病人喔
seems to be cured
好像可以治好
But since I haven't observed long enough
但是因為還沒有觀察夠久
So it takes experience
所以這還要累積經驗
But from the current data
但是從目前的資料看
Looking at these data, it looks like he is very rich, very rich
看這些數據,看起來是很有錢,很有錢錢
that this
那這個
The research is published in very top journals called Nature journals
研究是發表在非常頂尖的期刊,叫自然期刊
You may have heard
大家或許也有聽說過
That's actually this
那其實這個
It turns out that I like to use it as a reference
結果呢,是我很喜歡用來引用
to prove that it is possible that every normal human body
來證明說,可能每一個正常人體內
may be cancerous
可能都有癌性
That's how he does it, he does this experiment
那他做法是這樣,他就做這個實驗署
signature
導署
Then inject some chemical natural substances into this experimental department
然後將一些化學的自然物注射到這個實驗署
It seems that we usually come into contact with some natural substances
那就好像我們平常也會接觸到一些自然物質
You eat the sun that shines inside our environment
你吃的陽光照射,我們的環境裡面
Some natural substances exist, so we have been exposed to
存在一些自然物質,所以我們一直在捧接觸到
Then this experiment he found
那這個實驗他發現
He injected these natural substances, a few mice
他注射這些自然物質裡面,有少數老鼠
a tumor
就產生了腫瘤
then he knocks him out
那他就把他剔除掉
What he really wants to ask is, and
他真正要問的問題是說,還有
what about most mice
多數的老鼠呢
after two hundred days
經過兩百天之後
looks healthy
看起來很健康
so he asked a few questions
所以他問幾個問題
First, these contacts
第一,這些接觸過
Rats exposed to chemicals from tap water 200 days ago
兩百天前接觸過化學自來物質的老鼠
inside his body
他的身體裡面
Are there cancer cells?
是不是有癌細胞
This is the first question
這是第一個問題
The second question is
第二個問題是
if he
如果他
These mice have cancer cells in them
這些老鼠裡面有癌細胞
why doesn't he grow into a cancer
他為什麼不會長成一個癌症出來
Why does it still look healthy
為什麼看起來還是很健康
The third question is
第三個問題是
Is that because of the protection provided by the immune system in these mice
那是不是因為免疫系統提供的這些老鼠的保護作用
So he aimed at this experiment to answer these questions
所以他針對這個實驗就是要回答這些問題
His method is very simple
他的做法很簡單
Because in the laboratory where we do immunization
因為在我們做免疫的實驗室裡面
have some tools
有一些工具
We can regulate, control our immune system
我們可以去調控,控制我們的免疫系統
For example
比如說呢
For example this, if
比如說這個,如果
The immune system provides protection
免疫系統提供保護作用
Then if we destroy the immunity of this mouse
那我們如果把這個老鼠的免疫種破壞掉
So if the mouse has cancer cells
那如果這老鼠有癌細胞
Will it grow out then?
那它是不是就會長出來
So logically it should be easy to understand
所以邏輯上應該很容易理解
So that's really how it works
所以它做法真的就是這樣
It can use some antibody drugs
它就可以利用一些抗體的藥物
different types of immune cells
將不同種類的免疫細胞
clear up destroy
清除掉 破壞掉
it turns out that
結果它發現
If you destroy the immune cells of the mice
如果你破壞的老鼠的免疫細胞
especially cell
尤其是提細胞
this is us tonight
這是我們今天晚上
The most important protagonist of all is to lift the cells
所有的最重要的主角就是提細胞
it found that fifty percent of the mice
它發現百分之五十的老鼠
You see it's here two hundred days later
你看它在這邊兩百天之後
It puts this antibody drug in
它把這個抗體藥物進去
destroy our immune cells
將我們的免疫細胞破壞掉
As a result, once it destroys the cell
結果它一旦把這個提細胞破壞掉之後
You can see that more than half of the mice grow out of their seeds
你看一半以上的老鼠它種流就長出來
So this experiment clearly proves that
所以這一個實驗很清楚的證明說
In mice that had been exposed to chemicals
這些曾經接觸過化學自來物的老鼠體內
must have cancer cells
應該是有癌細胞的
It's just the mouse's immune system
只是這個老鼠的免疫系統
Especially the protection provided by kick cells
尤其是踢細胞 提供的保護作用
So although it has cancer cells, it can coexist peacefully with it
所以讓它雖然有癌細胞 可是可以跟它和平共存
It's fine if it doesn't grow cancer
它不長出癌症就好啦
so think about it
所以大家想想看
That means we can be exposed to chemicals that may be more
就是說我們能接觸化學物質可能更多
chemical source may be more
化學自來物可能更多
We have native objects in the environment
我們在環境裡面有自來物
There are chemical origins and physical origins
有化學自來物 物理的自來物
There are also some viruses that come from
還有一些病毒的自來物都有
But most of us are actually pretty healthy.
可是我們大部分人其實大部分都還很健康
He has to thank our immune system
他就要感謝我們的免疫系統
Do we really have cancer cells in our body?
我們身體內是不是真的有癌細胞
It's actually hard to judge
其實很難去評斷
This may depend on our most sophisticated
這個可能就是要看我們最精密的
Cancer cell detection system
癌細胞的檢測的系統
Well, now it’s probably CT, this kind of computerized tomography
那現在最近大概就是CT嘛,這種電腦斷層掃描
The computerized tomography scan, we all know its sensitivity
那電腦斷層掃描,大家知道它的靈敏度
If it is about 0.3 cm to 0.5 cm, it is difficult to confirm
如果是大概0.3公分到0.5公分,就一下就很難確認
a little bit, the size of a grain of rice
一點點,米粒大小
But everyone knows this, how many cancer cells are there in a tumor of this size
但是大家知道這個,這樣子的大小的腫瘤有多少癌細胞
Hundreds of millions, that is to say, the sensitivity of our current detection
上億個,也就是說我們現在的檢測的靈敏度
For example, below 0.3 cm, it is actually difficult for us to detect this kind of
在比如0.3公分以下,這種的我們其實很難去偵測到
But there are already very, very many cancer cells in it.
可是這裡面其實已經存在非常非常非常多癌細胞
Fortunately, most of the immune types are healthy.
那幸好大部分的免疫型都很健全
The other thing is that we have to take care of our immune system
那另外就是說我們要顧好自己的免疫系統
Then let it work normally
那讓它呢平時就發揮作用
So maintaining a healthy lifestyle has become very important
所以維持一個健康的生活型態,也變得很重要
Next, I will talk about immunotherapy from the beginning.
接下來我就從開始就講免疫治療的
The Past of Cancer Immunotherapy
癌症免疫治療的過去
This is about a very young doctor at that time.
這個就講一個那時候的很年輕的醫師
Called Dr. Corley
叫做科利醫師
This Dr. Corley was around the end of the 19th century
這位科利醫師大概19世紀末
he is a surgeon
他是有外科醫師
At that time there was only one treatment for cancer
在那個時候癌症的治療只有一種
It's surgery
就是手術
Traditional Therapeutic Radiation Today
現在的傳統治療放射線
Madam Juju hadn't discovered
居居夫人那時候還沒有發現
chemotherapy not yet
化療還沒有
Don't put off treatment later
不要把治療放更晚
The only thing is to cut
唯一就是割除
Dr. Corley found
科利醫師發現
he observed clinically
他在臨床上觀察
In fact, many of our medical advances are like this
其實很多我們的醫學的進展是這樣
Just start from observation
就是從觀察開始看齊
then you will be curious
然後你會好奇
Curiosity triggers your research motivation
好奇你就會引發你的研究動機
he found out
他發現是這樣
He found a patient in Fresh Stand
他發現有一個病人在Fresh Stand
With his surgeon expertise, he thinks this patient probably won't live long.
以他的外科醫師的專業 他認為這個病人大概活不了多久
However, this patient developed a bacterial infection during hospitalization.
可是呢 這個病人在住院期間發生了細菌的感染
He thought at that time, there were no antibiotics for humans
他想在那個時候 還沒有 人類還沒有抗生素
Bacterial infection is very serious
細菌感染是非常的嚴重
Then some patients may not make it through, and some patients may survive.
那有些病人可能就撐不過去 有些病人可以活下來
He discovered this Fresh Dan bacterial infection, repeated bacterial infections
他發現了這個Fresh Dan的細菌感染 發生重複性的細菌感染
But it is strange that after his bacterial infection is cured, he always disappears
可是很奇怪 就是他細菌感染好了之後 他總有消失
So this was a big shock to him.
所以這個對他來講就是很大震撼
Because for his profession, the cancer he judged is already a terminal cancer patient.
因為對他來講 這個專業 他判斷的這個癌症已經是個末期的癌症病人
how can it be good
怎麼會好
So he put forward a hypothesis
所以他提出一個假說
In fact, you see, our science is all about observation, making hypotheses, and making bold assumptions.
其實你看 我們科學都是觀察 提出假說 大膽假設
Be careful next time
接下來就小心求證
Then he did it and came up with a hypothesis. He thought maybe it was a bacterial infection and it was cured.
然後他做法 結果提出假說 他認為說 說不定是細菌感染 治好了
This Freshden's cancer
這個Freshden的癌症
Then he went back to find their hospital
然後他回去就找他們的醫院
this new york cancer hospital
這紐約的癌症醫院
Is there a similar case
是不是有相同的病例
As a result, he found more than 30 similar cases
結果他找到30幾個類似的病例
Bacterial infection occurs
發生細菌感染
As a result, almost half of the cancer disappeared
結果差不多一半癌症也消失
So this caused him to be more active
所以這引起他就更有現行
So he started to execute the first
所以他就開始執行第一次的
looks dangerous now
現在看起來是很危險的
a so-called human experiment
一個所謂人體試驗
He finds the next patient to see him
他就找到下一個跟他求診的病人
Called Signal Zola
叫做Signal Zola
Everyone look at this, he has a photo to keep
大家看這個他有照片留下來
have invested in
有投進來
Then it has metastasized to the lungs and variable glands
然後已經轉移到肺跟變滔腺
This patient probably won't live long.
這個病人他估計大概活不了太久
Then this case will carry out his clinical trial
那這科例就執行他的臨床試驗
Bacteria
將細菌
injected into his tumor
注射到他的腫瘤
In the end, I called once, twice, three times, but it didn't seem to work.
結果打一次,兩次,三次,好像都沒什麼用
He also does not cause infection
他也不會引起感染
Of course the tumor is fine
腫瘤當然就沒事
Then he wondered if his bacteria wasn't doing well
結果他想會不會他的細菌不太行
So I found this one
所以就找了這一位
Those who have attended junior high school, high school, or religious studies
上過國中、高中、聖物學的人
This is the famous Koho
這是鼎鼎大名的科霍
father of bacteriology
細菌學之父
He's the one who came up with the Koho collimator
科霍視準者就是他提出來的
german science prize
德國的科學獎
just go ask him
就去跟他要
because he invented a way to grow bacteria
因為他科霍發明了培養細菌的方法
So you get the purest, most powerful bacteria
所以你可以得到最純的、最強而有力的細菌
As a result, after he injected the bacteria
結果他注射這個細菌之後
Sure enough, it caused a serious bacterial infection.
果然就引發了很嚴重的細菌感染
chills, nausea, vomiting, fever
發冷、噁心、嘔吐、發燒
This isolated symptom occurs
發生這種單獨的症狀
This is a serious bacterial infection
這個就是嚴重的細菌感染
if found
如果查到的
Symptoms of this bacterial infection
這種細菌感染的症狀
What did you find?
結果呢 發現
This patient has cancer in his head
這個病人他的頭腥癌
It disappeared completely within two weeks.
也在兩個禮拜之內就完全消失了
Cancer is also under control
轉離癌也控制住
Then the patient will be discharged
那這病人就出院了
This was supposed to last a few weeks
這本來是認為撐不過幾個禮拜
eight more years
又多活了八年
But then his cancer came back
但是之後他癌症還是復發
But these eight years are earned
但是這八年是賺到的
The healthy ones lived for eight years
很健康的都活了八年
What about Koho?
那科霍呢
the collie
這個科利
he invented
他就發明了
He thought he was doing the right thing
他就認為他這樣子的做法是對的
for treatment
用來治療的
Therefore, during his decades as a criminal doctor
所以在他的刑醫的這幾十年裡面
He published about 1500 cases
他發表了大概1500個病例
he has 500 cases
他有500個病例
is effective for cancer
是癌症有顯著的療效
is one third
是三分之一
This is actually from the current point of view
這個其實是以現在的觀點來看
It is also an unlikely figure
也是一個不太可能達成的數字
but it's a pity to say
但是很可惜就是說
At that time, everyone didn't know about immunology
類在那個時候免疫學大家都還不曉得
no basis in immunology
沒有什麼免疫學的基礎
don't know how it works
也不知道它到底是怎麼作用的
Its biggest problem is that it can do it well and others can't do it
它最大問題是它做得出來別人做不出來
other people's consciousness can't do it
別人意識做不出來
for any medical action
因為任何一個醫療的行為
The method of medical treatment must be repeated
醫療的那個方法一定要再現行
That is to say, I did it at National Taiwan University.
也就是說我在台大做的
It should be done in City University
在城大應該要做出來
Otherwise, if you only rely on some individual reports
要不然的話你如果只憑一些個別的一些報導
The absence of recurrence does not actually constitute an effective medical
沒有再現行其實不能夠構成一個有效的醫療
So this is what we need to do clinical trials
所以這個也就是我們需要做臨床試驗
Different levels of clinical trials are a big reason
不同級別的臨床試驗很大的原因
So an early result of this Coly like this
所以這個Coly的這樣子的一個早期的結果
have received little attention from the medical profession.
就不太受到醫學界的重視
Slowly, after a few years
慢慢的之後再隔了不到幾年
Mrs. Gilly found Ray
Gilly夫人就發現了雷了
then start
然後就開始
Even entered the era of Radiation radiation therapy
甚至進入了Radiation 放射治療的年代
Then around 1940
那之後到了1940年左右
Discovery of chemical drug that kills cancer cells
發現化學的藥物可以殺癌細胞
entered the era of chemotherapy
就開始進入了化學治療的時代
then around 2000
然後到2000年左右
It was found that cancer cells have mutations in some genes than normal cells
發現癌細胞跟正常細胞有一些基因上面的突變
That can use some drugs to control these mutant receptors
那可以用一些藥物控制這些突變的receptors
This is called targeted therapy
這種叫標靶治療
it's listed here
就是列在這邊
Surgery Radiotherapy Chemotherapy Targeted Therapy
手術 放療 化療 標靶治療
Then this constitutes the mainstream of cancer treatment now.
那這就構成現在癌症的治療的主流
Immunotherapy has been only in academia
免疫治療一直只是在學界
And even in academia people don't quite believe
而且即使在學界大家還不太相信
until recently
一直到最近
These are the developments that I want to introduce to you after today.
就是我今天之後要跟大家介紹的這些發展
good
好
Alright, the next thing I want to do is to introduce to you
好 那接下來呢就是要跟大家介紹
the body's immune system
身體的免疫系統
The immune system is not actually developed to treat cancer
免疫系統其實不是發展出來對療治療癌症
Because of our surrounding environment
因為我們的周遭的環境裡面
There have always been a lot of vitamins
一直有非常多的維生物
Everyone is protected by the immune system without realizing it.
大家其實不失不覺都在受到免疫系統的保護
you don't know how precious it is
你不太知道它的珍貴
because everyone looks healthy
因為大家看起來都很健康
But you need to know the importance of the immune system to health
可是你要知道免疫系統對健康的重要性
it's actually really easy
其實很簡單
You can know it from immunocompromised patients
你可以從免疫缺陷病人就可以知道
If the patient
如果這個病人
Whether congenital or acquired
不管是先天性還是後天性
lack of immune system
缺少免疫系統
He can't survive under normal circumstances
他沒有辦法在一般的環境下存活
Like a famous example called Bobble Child
像有一個很有名的例子叫做Bobble Child
His innate immune switch
他先天性免疫切換
He lives in a segregated village
他住在隔離的隔離鄉裡面
and then all the activities
然後所有的一切的活動
must be performed in a sterile environment
都需要在無菌的環境下進行
Generally speaking, it is normal for us
一般來講對我們正常的
These dimensional creatures are not at all a problem
完全不是任何問題的這些維生物
Probably well known to him
有可能對他來講都是知名
The immune system is actually helping us deal with all these creatures
免疫系統其實在幫我們對付所有這些回生物
This is innate, each of us has
這個就是天生,我們每個人都有的
We just need to learn now
我們現在只是需要學習
How to apply it and train it
怎麼樣去應用它、訓練它
Let it help us fight the disease
讓它能夠對我們抵抗接病有幫助
But the immune system is actually doing two things at once
但是免疫系統其實它是一面兩任
it should have heard font immune disease
它應該聽過字體免疫病
If immune hyperactivation
如果免疫過度活化
or it was supposed to attack dimensional creatures
或者它本來應該要攻擊維生物
If it turns out to attack your own cells,
結果反過頭來攻擊你自己的細胞的話
that's an autoimmune disease
那是字體免疫病
Font immune disease is actually very difficult to treat
字體免疫病其實非常困難治療
related to genetics
跟遺傳有關係
So how to control the immune system
所以怎麼樣去控制免疫系統
Make it able to deal with alien invading dimensional creatures
讓它能夠對付外來的入侵的維生物
If it's cancer, let it fight the cancer
如果癌症的話,讓它對付癌細胞
But don't kill your own cells
但是又不要去殺到自己的細胞
then become a big
那就變成一個很大的
an important area
重要的一個領域
Then I will briefly introduce
那我現在簡單的介紹一下
immune system
免疫系統
all immune cells
所有人的免疫細胞
it has an immune
它都是有一個免疫的
Blast cells that we call bone marrow
叫我們叫骨髓的母細胞
hematopoietic stem cells
造血的幹細胞
Called Hematopoietis stem cells
叫Hematopoietis stem cells
In adults these hematopoietic stem cells
在成人這些造血幹細胞
is the marrow in our bones
是在我們的骨頭裡面的骨髓
Look at the red bone marrow
你看紅紅的那些骨髓
That hematopoietic stem cell
那這個造血幹細胞
It will be divided into two categories
它就會分化成兩大類
Myeloid Globlasts
一大類叫骨髓球母細胞
or lymphoblast
或者叫淋巴球母細胞
bone marrow blast
骨髓球母細胞
responsible for making our blood cells
負責來製造我們的血 cell 膽
erythrocyte
紅血球
it has a lot of phagocytes
它有很多的吞噬細胞
We are called white blood cells
我們叫白血球
so you see white blood cells
所以你們看到白血球
Another large group we call lymphoblasts
另外一大類我們稱之為淋巴球母細胞
These lymphoblasts are responsible for making T lymphocytes
這些淋巴球母細胞負責製造T淋巴球
And B lymphocytes
還有B淋巴球
Everyone has heard of antibodies
大家聽過抗體
Antibodies are mainly after activation of B lymphocytes
抗體主要就是有B淋巴球活化之後
These proteins that are produced and secreted into the blood
所製造出來的分泌到血液裡面的這些蛋白
Can recognize external whys
能夠辨識外來的為什麼
entire immune system
整個免疫系統
The most important category is probably this
最重要的分類大概就是這樣
that you want to phagocyte
就是你要吞噬細胞
Phagocyte encounters bacteria within the first instant
吞噬細胞在第一時間之內碰到細菌
devour it
還將它吞噬
We use the following reality to explain
我們用後面這張實在來解釋
Write a few slides for everyone to see
寫給大家看幾張投影片
This is seen with an electron microscope
這個是電子顯微鏡看到的
This is a white blood cell
這個是白血球
erythrocyte
紅血球
Red blood cells are much more numerous than white blood cells
紅血球的數量比白血球多得多
So let's look at red first
所以我們先看一下紅色
It is difficult for you to distinguish the electronic behavior of white blood cells
那這白血球在電子行為你很難去區分
Which are phagocytes
哪一些是吞噬細胞
Which ones are mention cells? They look similar
哪一些是提細胞 看起來是差不多
But if you do some special dyeing
但是你如果做一些特殊的染色
Like the hematology department, he can go to draw blood after it comes out
像血液科 他可以去抽血出來之後
He can do some special dyes and you'll see this form
他可以做一些特殊的染色 那你會看到這個形態
Let's say these are red blood cells
比如說這些是紅血球
Those are the white blood cells.
那這些呢 就是白血球
You see, the white blood cells look different, but here they look the same
你看這白血球的樣子其實不太一樣 在這邊看起來是一樣
It doesn't look the same on this side, it's just a four-neutral
在這邊看起來不太一樣 這個就是一個四中性的
leukocyte
白血球
This is a mononuclear ball
這個是一個單核球
Then this should be a four-acid white blood cell
那這個應該是一個四酸性的白血球
If you get leukemia
那如果得到白血病
you'll find that certain types of this
你就會發現呢 某一些種類的這個
A large increase in the number of white blood cells
白血球數量 大量的增加
Next, I will introduce to you
那接下來呢 我就是跟大家介紹
I clearly want to know how to deal with foreigners for a living
我明明想到底怎麼樣去對付外來為生
Everyone, look at this secret
大家看這秘密麻麻的
These tubular systems
這些管狀的系統
These are called lymphatic vessels
這我們稱之為淋巴管
And what about these little black balls?
然後這一顆一顆黑色的小球呢
want lymph nodes
要淋巴結
After the blood cells are made from that bone marrow
那血液細胞從那個骨髓製造出來之後
climbed into the blood vessel
爬到血管
Then search for blood vessels all over the body
然後會在全身尋著血管
with lymphatic circulation
跟淋巴管循環
first person to find it
去找它的第一人
if found
如果找到
It sends out the function of going straight to destroy the invading creatures
它就發出直行這個消滅入侵為生物的功能
can't find it
找不到呢
it has a certain lifespan
它有一定的壽命
it will die
它會死亡
after death
死亡之後
Our modeling mother cells continue to make these white blood cells
我們的造型母細胞就持續的再去製造這些白血球
So let's maintain a certain balance
所以讓我們維持一定的平衡
if cancer
如果是癌症
Chemo here has serious side effects
化療這裡有很嚴重的副作用
That is, it will cause the white blood cells to drop
就是它會造成白血球降低
Of course this becomes very susceptible to nosocomial infections
當然這變得很容易受到院內感染
In fact, because chemotherapy drugs will kill our hematopoietic mother cells
其實因為化療的藥物會殺死我們的造血母細胞
After killing, its ability to produce white blood cells declines
殺死之後 它製造白血球的功能就下降
will become less
就會變少
So these phagocytes in our body
所以我們身體的這些吞噬細胞
It will be the first time of course there are aliens as creatures once invaded
它會在第一時間 當然有外來為生物 一旦入侵
It will be the first time these alien creatures
它會在第一時間便是這些外來為生物
swallow
吞掉
So everyone phagocytes
所以大家吞噬細胞
I'll show you this video later
我等一下會給大家看這個影片
After swallowing, of course, many bacteria are controlled in this way
吞掉之後 當然就很多細菌就這樣子被控制好了
But some are more pathogenic
但是有一些病原性更厲害
it is not afraid of phagocytes
它不怕吞噬細胞
Like the phagocytic cells I mentioned, it has another characteristic
那像我講的吞噬細胞它還有一個特性
it will after phagocytosis bacteria
它會在吞噬細菌之後
it transforms into what are called antigen presenting cells
它會轉化成所謂的抗原呈現細胞
It will carry this germ, the devoured germ
它會攜帶著這個病菌 吞噬的病菌
Enter the 08 system
進入08系統
Go to Section 08
進入08節
In Section 08, it will encounter the T cell just mentioned
在08節它就會碰到剛剛講的那個T細胞
Then this antigen presenting cell is exposed to activate 08 cell in section 08
然後這個抗原呈現細胞在08節接觸活化08細胞
triggers a germ-specific immune response
引發病菌專醫性的免疫反應
Then what about these 08 cells
然後之後這些08細胞呢
Through blood circulation and 08 circulation
會藉由血液的循環跟08的循環
find invading bacteria
找到入侵的細菌
destroy it
消滅它
This is how all our immune systems work
這就是我們所有的免疫系統的作用的原理
Then I will show you the video now
那我現在給大家看一下影片
this is a phagocyte
這是一個吞噬細胞
an electron to kill bacteria
去殺死細菌的一個電子
a microscope film
一個顯微鏡的影片
wait a minute
等一下等一下
Here spread a neutrophil is
在這 spread a neutrophil is
red blood cells in the middle
在中間的紅血球
Because some people may not understand English well
因為有些人可能英文聽不太清楚
i was explaining
我有在解釋
This is a four middle white blood cell
這是一個四中間的白血球
it's just bacteria
這隻是細菌
it's just red blood cells
這隻是紅血球
Staphylococcus aureus
就是金黃色葡萄球菌
start chasing this
開始追這張
Chemicals in the middle of bacteria four
細菌四中間的化學物質
attract it to chase
吸引它去追
So the Uighurs it produces are called phagocytes
所以它生出的維族叫吞噬細胞
So it's called a phagocyte
所以這叫吞噬細胞
right
對
oh no
喔那不是啊
this it has some that
這個它有一些那個
that
那個
Adjustment
調整
so you see it says
所以你看它就是說
if you use those
你如果用那些
To see our body's detailed multi-dimensional organisms
去看我們身體細很多維生物的
Once the software is hacked
一旦入侵軟體之後
Phagocytes will immediately
吞噬細胞馬上就會
become a cell
變成一個細胞
so it is
所以它就是
After hacking software
入侵軟體之後
Phagocytes immediately go after it
吞噬細胞馬上就過去追逐它
that swallows it up
那把它吞噬掉
After talking about devouring
那剛剛講吞噬掉之後
it will go to section 08 first
它會先進入08節
present antigen to cells
呈現抗原給提細胞
so this is the first step
所以這個是第一步
Phagocytosis
吞噬作用
ok then let's
好那我們再
look at
看下
next
接下來
Subtitler Zither Harp
字幕製作人Zither Harp
Well, here, this one looks like bacteria, over there hairs, bacteria are completely different from our human cells
好,那這裡,這隻看起來像細菌,那邊毛,細菌跟我們人體的細胞是完全不同
So for the immune system, this job is very easy, it is very easy, it is easy to distinguish which are bacteria and which are cells of our limbs
所以對免疫系統來講,這工作很輕鬆,它很輕鬆的,很容易分辨哪些是細菌,哪些是我們肢體的細胞
It does not attack its own cells, it attacks bacteria, and bacteria have some special structures, which we call pathogen-associated molecular structures
它不要去攻擊,自己的細胞,它攻擊細菌,那細菌它有一些特別的結構,我們稱之為病原體相關分子結構
Those who speak English don’t need to read it, because the fraiserin means to become hairy
那這些英文的大家就不用去看,那其中這個fraiserin就是變毛的意思
Then there are some components called lipopolisaccharide, cell B, bacterial cell B, human cells do not have cell B
那還有一些這個叫lipopolisaccharide,細胞B的,細菌細胞B的成分,人類細胞是沒有細胞B的
So of course there is no lps, but the plate below is its receptor, the receptor that recognizes these molecular structures
所以當然沒有這個lps,那下面這一盤呢,就是它的受體,辨識這些分子結構的受體
Some of these receptors recognize different molecular structures
有些不同的這些受體可以辨識不同的分子結構
So this is the principle why our phagocytic cells can find bacteria and viruses to swallow them
所以這個就是為什麼我們吞噬細胞可以去吞可以去找到細菌病毒去吞噬它的原理
Phagocytosis when bacteria just don't see V. aureus being phagocytized by our secondary neutrophils
吞噬當細菌剛剛不看到金黃色葡萄酒菌被我們的次中性血球吞噬掉
One thing happens after devouring
吞噬之後會發生一件事情
Just looking for our artist, is it a big principle or how bacteria phagocytosis
就是找我們美工是化的 原理大還是怎樣細菌吞噬細胞
It will have a different molecular structure on the bacteria due to phagocytosis
它會因為吞噬細胞而細菌上面有些不同的分子結構
In addition to devouring it, it actually activates it
它除了吞噬它之外其實也會活化它
it gets fierce
它變得很兇
It's pretty empty after phagocytizing bacteria
吞噬細菌之後它就變得很空無油力
an activated phagocyte
就變成一個活化型的吞噬細胞
Activated phagocytes have
活化型的吞噬細胞才有
Ability to present antigens to T cells
能力呈現抗原給T細胞
If you are just one of these
你如果只是一個這種
original antigenicity
不太有利的這些原來抗原性
It presents to T cells that function is actually poor
它呈現給T細胞功能其實是很差的
What about activated antigen-presenting cells?
那活化型的抗原呈現細胞呢
It can present antigens, which are derived from bacteria
它可以呈現抗原,那抗原是來自細菌
right if it's kennzer
對不對,如果是Kennzer
tumor antigen
癌症的話,那就是腫瘤抗原
But, it also needs to represent co-stimulatory molecules
那但是呢,它還要表現共同刺激分子
It has to represent cell technology
它要表現細胞技術
This is only activated
這只有活化的這種
Phagocytes, which look fierce, have this ability
看起來很兇的吞噬細胞,才具備這種能力
Then
然後
Next this activated phagocyte
接下來這個活化的吞噬細胞
I just talked about antigens, it shows antigens, a little bit of red
剛剛講抗原,它呈現抗原,紅色這一點點
co-stimulatory molecular cell technology
然後共同刺激分子細胞技術
act together on a single T cell
共同作用在一個T細胞上面
When T cells activate
當T細胞活化
Split
分裂
differentiation
分化
he lived a long time
他活得很久
What about T cells like this?
那這樣子的T細胞呢也是一樣
He was also a very kind T cell
他本來也是一個很善良的T細胞
After being educated by antigen presenting cells
被抗原呈現細胞教育之後
He'll also turn into an empty T-cell
他也會變成一個空無有力的T細胞
and he will split
而且呢他會分裂
He has an immunity, that system has a characteristic
他有個免疫那個系統有個特性
that is, T cells
就是說T細胞
A certain type of T cell, such as the T cell activated by this bacterium
某一種T細胞比如說被這個細菌活化的T細胞
He can only recognize this bacterium
他只能夠認識這個細菌
He doesn't care about other enemies
他對其他的敵人他是不管
For example, if I'm working on the hepatitis B virus
比如說像我在研究B型肝炎病毒
What if antigenic phagocytes present this hepatitis B virus
如果呢抗原吞噬細胞呈現這個B型肝炎病毒
antigen to this T cell
抗原給這個T細胞
The trained T cells only recognize liver B
訓練出來的T細胞他只辨識B肝
He doesn't care about other enemies
其他的敵人他不管
This is what vaccines do
這個就是疫苗的作用
After we have a certain vaccine
我們要打某一種疫苗下去之後
these immune responses
引發的這些免疫反應
Only recognize this vaccine
只辨識這一種疫苗
other viruses
其他的病毒
sorry he doesn't care
對不起他不管
So we have to find the right antigen
所以我們要找到對的抗原
to elicit a response to this antigen
去引發針對這個抗原的
T cell response
T細胞反應
That
那
microorganism
微生物
You can easily know what his antigen is
你很容易知道他抗原是什麼
But cancer is hard for you to know
可是cancer你就很難知道
cancer cells
cancer i細胞
It's actually a change in your own cells
它其實是你自己的細胞變化來的
It's actually very, very similar to your own cells
它跟你自己的細胞其實非常非常像
I just talked about the immune system
那剛剛講過免疫系統
actually training
其實在訓
exist
在
in the process of growing
在那個生長的過程裡面
it will have received an education
它會接收過一個教育
We call it negative selection
我們叫做negative selection
in immune cells
就是在免疫細胞
Trained in T cells
在T細胞訓練出來
It does not recognize antigens on its own cells
它不會辨識自己細胞的抗原
avoid autoimmune disease
就叫避免自體免疫病
But because the i cells are different from your own cells
可是因為i細胞又跟你的自己細胞
almost the same
幾乎是一樣的
So the immune system basically doesn't recognize him
所以免疫系統基本上不認識他
or don't want to know him
或者不想認識他
In this situation
那這樣狀況之下
Is there a way to train the immune system
有沒有辦法去訓練免疫系統
separate
就分別
because of i-cell disease
因為i細胞關症的東西
Now scientific research is more and more clear
現在科學研究越來越清楚
found that although it looks a lot alike
發現它雖然很像很像
but not exactly the same
可是並不完全一樣
Because if it's exactly the same it won't become a cancer cell
因為如果完全一樣它就不會變成癌細胞
So we find some differences
所以我們就找到一些相異的地方
train your immune system
訓練你的免疫系統
to identify these differences
去辨識這些相異的地方
if it really works
如果真的能夠成功
It can specifically attack cancer cells
它就可以很專一的去攻擊癌細胞
Achieve the effect of healing Kensel
達到治療Kensel的效果
So there is actually a concept here
所以這邊其實有個很概念
The immune system is inactive under normal conditions
免疫系統在正常狀況下它是不活化的
It only activates when it touches an enemy
它只有碰到敵人的時候它才會活化
when the enemy is eliminated
當敵人消滅之後
It means that those activated cells will die in large numbers
它也就那些活化的細胞就會大量的死亡
So this is what was just said
所以這個就是剛剛講過的
These T cells have several properties
這些T細胞有幾個特性
the first one it will split a lot
第一個它會大量的分裂
When you encounter, say, the hepatitis B virus
當你碰到比如說B型肝炎病毒
To deal with liver B, the T cells will divide in large numbers
對付B肝的T細胞就大量的分裂
This number becomes many
這數目就變得很多
You can effectively control invasive sanitary species
你能夠有效地去控制入侵的衛生物
The second is medical expertise
第二是專醫性
activated T cells
這一群活化的T細胞
I only know this one virus that invaded
只認識入侵的這一個病毒
it doesn't care
其他的它不管
So sometimes we have to get a lot of vaccines
所以我們有時候疫苗就要打很多種
play a dozen
打十幾種
train different T cells
訓練出不同的T細胞
different G8,G9 cells
不同的G8,G9細胞
against different bacteria
對付不同的細菌
and memory
還有就記憶性
after a vaccination
打一記疫苗之後
some are lifetime
有些是終身有效
Because T cells are constantly replicating molecules by themselves
因為T細胞會自己不斷的複製分子
knitting
針織
So when we meet again next time
所以當下次再碰到的時候
It can be trained very quickly
它又可以很快速地訓練
So it has these basic properties
所以它有這些基本的特性
Expertise and memory
專醫性和記憶性
this is very good
這個就非常好
because our cancer cells
因為我們的癌細胞
We want to train T cells
我們希望訓練出來T細胞
only medical
只有專醫性
it only targets cancer cells
它只對付癌細胞
not to deal with our normal cells
不要去對付我們的正常細胞
memory is also very good
有記憶性也非常好
your metastatic cancer cells
你那些轉移的癌細胞
not yet killed
暫時沒殺掉
But we have T cells if they are still there
可是我們有T細胞如果還在
It can help you train again in the long run
它可以長期地再幫你訓練
Then you don't care where the diversion is to hide
那你不管那個轉移來躲到什麼地方去
Your T-C bag can track it
你T-C包都可以去追蹤它
Then achieve the effect of long-term control
那這樣就達到長期控制的效果
like just saw that mouse
就好像剛剛看到那個老鼠
It actually has cancer cells
它其實還有癌細胞
But because it has a sound immune system, it is not afraid
可是因為它有健全的免疫系統 所以它也不怕
It can still maintain a roughly healthy state of life
它還是可以維持大概一個健康的生活狀態
Then let me show you
那接下來我給大家看一下
It's the trained T-C bag, it's useless to stay in Section 08
就是訓練好的T-C包 它留在08節是沒用的
Because its enemy is not in the 08 section
因為它的敵人不在08節
It goes to find its invading vitamins, which are bacteria.
它去找到它入侵的維生物 就是細菌
If it's a cancer cell, it finds the metastatic cancer cells
如果是癌細胞 它找到轉移的癌細胞
It can't just stay in section 08
它不能只留在08節
Then there are some complicated principles
那這邊就有一些很複雜的原理
then i will describe a little bit
那我就稍微敘述一下
watch a video later
等一下會看一個影片
That's a viral infection
那這個是病毒染染
1 The phagocytic cell will of course swallow it
1 那這個吞噬細胞當然就吞它了
After swallowing it, it will also be at the site of the infection
吞它之後 它同時也會在感染的部位
inflammatory reaction
發炎反應 紅種熱痛的這種
Inflammatory reaction?
發炎的反應嗎?
At this time, there will actually be some
那這個時候其實會有一些
compartmentalizing hormone and adsorbin
區化激素跟吸附蛋白
present at the site of infection
表現在被感染部位的
capillaries
微血管
above blood vessels
血管上面
these in the blood
血液裡面的這些
White blood cells when it goes in
白血球 當它進過的時候
It interacts with these adsorbed proteins
它會跟這些吸附蛋白作用
Then the white blood cells
然後這白血球呢就
Can
可以
won't leave so quickly
不會這麼快速的離開
It rolls over the infection site
它就會在感染部位呢發生滾動
out of shape
就變形
divert transfer into our organization
轉路 轉移進去我們的組織
compartmentalization
藉由區化作用
find inflamed tissue
找到發炎的組織
The inflamed tissue is actually the site of the infection.
那發炎的組織其實就是感染的部位
Then by looping like this
然後藉由是這樣子循環呢
can be expelled from the blood vessel
可以齁 從血管裡面
leave blood vessel
離開血管
Find where the enemy is attacking
找到敵人攻擊的部位
If it's cancer, find the cancer cells
如果是癌症就找到癌細胞
If it is a bacterial infection, find the site of the bacterial infection
如果是細菌感染就找到細菌感染的部位
to destroy it
要消滅它
OK, let's see what happens next.
好 那我們接下來呢就看
then you cut the video
那你斷影片
Lukasite is white
Lukasite是白血型的
Usually it's inside a blood vessel
平常它是血管裡面
It's the inflamed area
就是發炎的部位
Bacterial infection releases cytokines
被細菌感染的釋放細胞激素
blood vessels at the site of infection
讓感染部位的血管
Expressed Adsorbin
表現吸附蛋白
to break
要斷掉
Appraisal component
鑑合成分
Identify the parts of the ingredients
把鑑合成分的部位
make them close
讓它們能夠靠近
sugars on white blood cells
白血球上的糖類
combine
結合
They start rolling in the veins
它們就開始在血管裡面滾動
sugars on white blood cells
白血球上的糖類
or by cell
或藉由細胞細胞
really insist
是真的堅持
Enter
進入
then the inflamed area
然後發炎的部位
Parts that have not been identified
沒有被鑑合成分的部位
Then find the inflamed site, which is the site of bacterial infection, and eliminate it
然後去找到這個發炎部位,就是細菌感染的部位,去消滅它
it's a live animation
它這是一個真人的動畫
Here everyone see, this is an artery
這邊大家看,這是動脈
This is the front
這邊是前脈
This direction is the direction of blood flow
這個方向就是血流的方向
Probably the flow speed is very fast, but in fact there are many, many blood cells
大概流速度很快,但其實很多很多血球
Then some white blood cells are absorbed here
那有一些白血球是吸附在這裏吸完病
some of them have entered the organization
那有一些已經進到組織了
You see, all these blood cells are absorbed in the veins
那大家看,所有這些血球的吸附都是在靜脈
The arterial bleeds, blood cells cannot absorb
那動脈的排泡,血球沒辦法吸附
thanks then , some are crawling
那謝謝,有一些正在爬行
some have gone in
那有一些已經進去了
then if you
那你如果
This, this has entered the organization
這個,這個已經進入組織了
This has entered your organization
這個已經進入了你的組織了
out of blood vessels into tissue
離開血管進入組織了
It is for you to see the cells inside the blood vessel
它為了要讓你看到這個血管裏面的細胞
clamp the blood vessels
把血管夾起來
So you see, so many cells can't flow now
所以你看,這麼多細胞,現在流不動
So you can see, very, very cells inside that blood vessel
所以你可以看到,非常非常細胞在那個血管裡面
then turn it on
那它再把它上開
blood starts flowing again
血又開始流
As soon as you let it go, it starts flowing again
一把它放開,又開始流
So our blood vessels are full of these blood vessels
所以我們血管裡面充滿了這些血管
So, the T cells after education
所以呢,就是受教育之後的這個T細胞
Involved in blood vessels
介入了血管
Then, through the effect just mentioned called adsorption
然後藉由剛剛講的叫吸附的作用
find the enemy it wants to attack
找到它要攻擊的敵人
then go in and destroy it
然後進去消滅它
ok , let ' s see next
好,那我們接下來再看
Lukasites are white blood cells
Lukasites are white blood cells
ok then next
好 那接下來
Actually I don't know
其實我 我不知道
But it doesn’t seem to be because oil should be fat, it’s in the blood, I think
但是好像不是 因為油的話應該是脂肪嘛 就血液裡面 我看
When it is very oily, there will be a lot of that and that lipid in it
很油的時候裡面會有很多那個那個 lipid
Will this ingredient be in it?
這成分在裡面 會不會因此
It causes the blood cells not to absorb and don’t imagine that the principle of water pipes is not the same
造成血球不會吸附 而且不要不要把想像水管這個原理不太一樣
But will it be true? In fact, when we do science, there is evidence to speak for itself. So
但是到底是不是會 其實我們做科學是有一份證據說一份話 所以
don't know
不太知道
but
但是
It must be bad for your health
對健康一定是不好的啦
especially for that new blood vessel
尤其是對那個新血管
sure it must be bad
很確定是一定不好的
then next is
那接下來就是
Didn't he just go in
他剛剛不是已經進到
Is the inflamed area right?
發炎部位對不對
So if you find that infected cell, how does he kill him?
那如果找到那個感染的細胞 他怎麼殺他的
show him next
接下來就給他看
current
目前的
this this video this is a
這個這個影片 這是一個
electron microscope photo
電子顯微鏡的照片
A is the target cell is the Target Cell
A就是標的細胞就是Target Cell
So this could be a virus-infected cell
那這可以是被病毒感染的細胞
or cancer cells
或者是癌細胞
Then this CTL
然後這個CTL
These are called killer T cells
這個我們叫殺手型T細胞
Here I am called T cell, this is it
這邊我叫T細胞,就是這個
Then it recognizes the antigen by this
然後它藉由這個辨識抗原
followed by T cell binding
跟著T細胞結合
Atrophy of target cells after binding
結合之後會造成標的細胞的萎縮
Within minutes the target cells begin to shrink
幾分鐘之內標的細胞就開始萎縮了
Because after it combines it will dissolve some mold
因為它結合之後它會將一些溶解霉
combined it creates a channel
結合之後它就製造了一個通道
Let this killer, some lytic mold in this T cell
將這個殺手,這個T細胞裡面的一些溶解霉
Injected through this channel
藉由這個通道注射進去
This target cell to attack
這個要攻擊的這個標的細胞
Then the dissolving mold will work after it goes in.
那這個溶解霉進去之後就發揮作用
Let the target cell start shrinking in a few minutes
讓這個標的細胞幾分鐘就開始萎縮
Then its cell membrane will form some protruding small bubbles
接著它細胞膜就會形成一些突起的小泡泡
Then the last cell dies
那最後這個細胞就死亡
die
死亡
After that, everyone, everyone, look at the holes one by one.
那之後大家看,大家看這個一個一個一個孔洞
this is in
這個就是在
Add ginger cells to break through
加薑細胞給打穿
what is this cell
那這細胞是甚麼
this is the whole process
這個就是它整個的過程
I'll come then
那我來
control the time
控制一下時間
We haven't even talked about the protagonist Ai Zheng yet.
我們現在都還沒講到主角埃政的
Don't let him talk for so long
這個就不要讓他講那麼久
Let everyone see it directly
直接給大家去看
good
好
This is a white blood cell
這個是一顆白血球
This is a T cell
這是T細胞
This is the target cell, the antigen on it
這個是標的細胞,它上面的抗原
then after combining it with
然後它結合之後
will dissolve some concentrated mold
會將一些濃解霉
inject into
注射到
target cell
標的細胞
that makes the target cell die
那讓這個標的細胞死亡
we'll see next
我們接下來再看
there should be one
應該有一個
This is a virus-infected cell
這個是被病毒感染的細胞
before he was killed
他沒有被殺死之前
He keeps releasing these viruses
他一直釋放這些病毒
He will kill himself and the virus will come out
他會自殺病毒出來
We kill after TGPOL passes
我們TGPOL過去之後殺掉
Of course he won't know about the virus after killing it
殺掉之後他當然就不會知道病毒
So this is a principle of controlling viral infection
所以這個是控制病毒感染的一個原理
He has electron microscope pictures next
他接下來有電子顯微鏡的照片
This is one of his Target Sales
這是一個他的Target Sales
This is white shoes
這個是白鞋出貨
after combining
結合之後
He now has a channel called Bridge
他現在有一個這種通道叫Bridge
dissolve some mold
將一些溶解霉
everyone see
大家看到
inject it
注射進去
After injection, it causes the shrinkage of the target cells
注射進去之後造成這個標的細胞的萎縮
the cell membrane
這個細胞膜
transmission
傳動
look at it
你看它
in transmission
在傳動
In the end, the cell is too big to die.
最後這個細胞大就不行了
produce some small bubbles, then decompose
產生一些小泡泡,就分解掉
This T cell, it can find its next enemy
這個T細胞,它可以再去找它下一個敵人
If this is an I cell, that's hopefully going to happen
如果這個是一個I細胞,那就很希望發生
And it's I cells, wherever they hide, T cells have the ability to find them
而且就是I細胞,躲在什麼地方,T細胞都有能力去找到它
Next, what is immunotherapy?
接下來要講什麼是免疫治療
The first one is really using your own body
第一張實在是利用你自己的身體
In fact, it should be that you use your own body's immune system
其實應該就是你利用你自己身體的免疫系統
to cure disease
去治療,疾病
immunotherapy
廣稱就叫做免疫治療
Here are some examples
這邊就舉一些例子
or immune watermelon, or immune-related proteins
或是免疫西瓜,或是免疫相關的蛋白
To treat a disease, it's called immunotherapy
來治療一種疾病,就叫免疫治療
There are two categories, active immunotherapy and passive immunotherapy
有分成兩大類,主動是免疫治療,跟被動是免疫治療
Active is immunotherapy, that is, using some drugs or vaccines
主動是免疫治療,就是利用一些藥物,或者疫苗
Activate the patient's own immune miniature
活化這個病人自己的免疫小型
That is to say, this immune miniature is actually not stimulated, but stimulated.
也就是說這個免疫小型,其實並不是打刺激,而是被刺激出來
For example, the vaccine itself does not have the ability to resist bacteria
比如說疫苗本身沒有抵抗細菌能力
It triggers the immune system of the immunized person, and it produces a protective effect
它是引發了被免疫人的免疫系統,它才會產生保護效果
So the real active people are produced by the vaccine
所以真正的主動的人是被疫苗產生出來的
So this is what we call active immunization, for example, you are injected with type B liver cancer vaccine
所以這個我們稱為主動的免疫,比如說你注射B型肝癌疫苗
Afterwards, the injected baby will produce specialized comprehensive antibodies
之後注射的小Baby就會產生專醫性的綜合性抗體
Then it is no longer afraid of hepatitis B virus infection
那它就不再怕B型肝癌病毒感染
So this antibody is produced by the baby, not injected by us
所以這抗體是小Baby產生的,並不是我們注射進去的
So this is what we call active immunotherapy
所以這我們叫做主動式的免疫治療
Then there are some critical situations
然後有一些狀況很危急
Because it takes a while for a vaccine to develop
因為疫苗它的產生需要一段時間
Then when you are infected by a virus
那當你被病毒一旦感染之後
it can't wait that long
它等不到那一段時間
it just keeps replicating
它就病毒一直在複製
Waiting until your grass is not easy to produce is already bad
等到你草不容易產生出來已經不好
So when you say you accidentally get rubbed on your body
所以當你比如說你不小心被身頭擦到
And know that this is like the love stagnation virus
而且知道說這個比如愛滯病毒
There is this heteromorphic hepatic heart virus
有這個異形肝心病毒
Then you can no longer use vaccines at this time
那你這個時候你不能再用疫苗
Because it's too late
因為太來不及了反不計及
At this time, a large amount of antibodies are injected into the
這個時候是打大量的抗體進去
So this antibody is produced by our event
所以這個抗體就是我們事件就製造好了
then type in
然後就打進去
So is tetanus
破傷風也是這樣
you got rubbed by that rusty nail
你被那個生鏽釘子擦了
Hurry up and call
趕快去打
That tetanus is vaccinated
那個破傷風是打疫苗
but some are poisonous
但是有一些要蛇毒
Snake venom is directly injected with snake venom serum
蛇毒是直接就打蛇毒血清
Synthesize the bacteria or virus
綜合掉這個細菌或者是病毒
or these toxins they produce
或者是他們產生的這些毒素
This is called passive immunity
這個就叫做被動式免疫
are now used as cancer immunizers
都現在都用來做癌症的免疫者
The next example in this period will come to an end.
接下來這個期的例子就告一段
our body's immune system
我們身體的免疫者
The immune person that everyone does not know in the body
大家身體之內不曉得的免疫者
It turned out to be so effective
竟然是這麼有效
But his example might scare me
但是他這個例子我可能會嚇到
in roman times
在羅馬時期
The average human life span is only in their 20s
人類平均生命只有20幾歲
His so-called life is
他所謂的生命是
as long as you are born
只要你出生出來
with death
跟死亡的
The death of the little baby is also counted
小Baby死亡也算
because at that time
因為那個時候
think about it
大家想想看
that's us now
就是我們現在
Born in Taiwan
一出生之後在台灣
You get a dozen different vaccines
你要打十幾種不同的疫苗
why? because
為什麼?因為
Babies are very susceptible to infection
嬰兒嬰兒的死亡非常容易受感染
He may have received his mother in the first half of the year
他一開始前半年可能受母
mother protection
媽媽保護
if breastfeeding
如果有餵母奶的話
but after that
可是之後呢
He needs to immunize himself
他需要讓他自己產生免疫的作用
to protect himself
來保護他自己
But for a while, it's actually quite dangerous
可是就這一段時間其實是相當危險
So need to be vaccinated
所以需要打疫苗
to accelerate the effect of this protection
來加速這個保護的效果
Even in medieval England in the 1500s
即使到了1500年的中世紀英國
Its overall average condition is still around 30 years
它整個平均狀況還是在30年左右
it's been a long time now
現在就很久了
Now both Japan and Taiwan are 80 years old
現在在日本 台灣都到80歲
But some countries are still at 50
但有些國家還是在50歲
In fact, this is a very important human invention
其實這邊很重要的一個人類的發明
is the vaccine
就是疫苗
I just said that vaccines are actually active immunity.
剛剛講過疫苗其實這是主動式的免疫
You see how well this vaccine protects us
你看這疫苗對我們的保護效果
These are what you see in Taiwan
這些就是你看到的台灣的
Almost the world's little despicable
幾乎全世界小卑鄙
vaccines to be given
要打的疫苗
For example, like the small ringgit vaccine
比如說像小馬幣疫苗
Over 21,000 cases in 1952
在1952年的時候有21000多個病例
now zero
現在是零
You see everything else is like this
你看其他都是這樣
so in the 1950s
所以在1950年代
If you look at the top ten causes of death
你如果去看十大死亡原因
definitely more like
絕對更像
completely different now
現在完全不一樣
Many of these infectious diseases should be
應該很多都會是這些infectious diseases
So the shape of human disease is changing
所以人類疾病形態在改變
the vaccine was invented
之後發明這疫苗
So our lifespan is extended
所以我們的壽命就延長了
After the extension, we will face another form of disease
延長之後我們就要面對另外一種形態的疾病
cancer
癌症
So now cancer is our worst enemy
所以現在癌症是我們最大的敵人
But come to think of it, vaccines
但是想想看就是說疫苗
Help us deal with the top killers of our past
幫忙我們對付我們過去的那些頭號的殺手
Is there any way to use the same method now
那現在有沒有辦法用同樣的方法
to activate the immune system
來活化免疫系統
Then it's not about dealing with alien dimensional creatures at this time.
那這個時候不是對付外來的維生物
It's to deal with the cancer cells after the transformation of your body's cells
而是對付你身體細胞轉型之後的癌細胞
Is there a way for the immune system to achieve this character?
那免疫系統有沒有辦法達成這個人物
So we're going to introduce you to
所以我們接下來要跟大家介紹
Then the system he uses is just introduced to you
那他用的系統就是剛剛跟大家介紹
What are these killers?
這些什麼殺手細
Phagocytes or T cells
吞噬細胞或T細胞
still these things
還是這些東西
good
好
Here are the top 10 causes of death
這邊就是看10大死亡的原因
Cancer is now number one
癌症現在都是第一位
Probably close to 30%
大概接近30%
But it wasn't like that in the 1950s
可是1950年代不是這樣的
That's because a lot of the big part is the vaccine development wages
那是因為很多很大的部分是疫苗的發展工資
Next comes cancer cells, cancer
接下來就是癌細胞 癌症
Cancer doesn't just pop up out of thin air.
癌症其實它不是憑空就冒出來的
In fact, it is also a process, because many of you should know
其實也是經過 因為大家很多人應該都曉得
everyone has culture theory
大家有文化的理論
try to survive in the earth environment
試著生存 在地球環境裡面
Organisms best suited to this environment can survive
最適合這個環境的生物可以存活下來
When the environment changes you need to have some mutation
當環境改變 你需要有一些mutation
Some genetic variation is required
需要有一些基因上的變異
This mutation makes you more suitable for this environment
這個變異讓你更適合這個環境的
In this group, probably most of the members of the group died
這個族群裡面 可能大部分的族群的成員都死亡
These organisms can stay because they are suitable for this environment
這些因為適合這個環境的生物就可以留下來
This is called things, those who live in peace, those who live in the world
這叫做物,靜天者,世者生存
Cancer cells are actually produced in this way
癌細胞其實就是這樣產生出來的
This edited theory of what we call cancer
這個我們稱之為癌症的緬義的編輯理論
I will use this very complicated picture to introduce it to him.
我就用這個很複雜的圖跟他介紹一下
The gray cells are some normal cells
這個灰色的細胞是一些正常細胞
when it's stimulated by a number of different carcinogens
當它受到一些不同的致癌因子的刺激之後
Of course it will transform, and some will turn into cancer cells
當然會轉型,有一些會變成癌細胞出來
So I just said that many people may have cancer cells physiologically
所以我剛剛講過,很多人生理可能都有癌細胞
But in the early days, during the elimination period
可是在早期的時候,在消滅期這個時候
We have a very good and sound Burmese system here
我們這裡有很好的健全的緬義系統
Kill him as soon as your cancer cells come out
你癌細胞一出來就把他殺掉
So you don't even know, you still feel healthy
所以你根本也不曉得,你還是覺得很健康
Most people are in this state
大部分的人是在這個狀態
But some are still sick
可是有一些還在病人
Cancer is becoming more and more
現在的癌症變得越來越多
this starts
這就開始
Because what the IC package just said
因為IC包剛剛講的
survival of the fittest
適者生存
IC package if he is not applicable in
IC包如果他不適用在
who here chooses him
這邊誰去選擇他
who is going to attack him
誰去攻擊他
is the immune system
就是免疫系統
what does he apply
他要適用什麼
he has to adapt the immune system
他要適應免疫系統
If he can adapt the immune system
如果他能夠適應免疫系統
It's because he's not afraid of the immune system
就是他不怕免疫系統
he has a chance to survive
他就有機會可以存活下來
So there are some IC packages
所以有一些IC包
changes in his genes
他的基因的改變
His ability to attack immune cells
讓他對免疫細胞攻擊的能力
Greater tolerance
承受度更大
So these few IC packages
所以這些少數的IC包
survive
就可以存活下來
At this time, we enter the so-called coexistence period.
這個時候就進入所謂的共存期
The coexistence period is your IC package
共存期就你的IC包
Although in
雖然在
But you can't go too far
可是你也不能太過分
You just maintain a certain amount
你就是維持一定的數量
that's good
這樣就好了
I obviously controlled you first
我明明先有控制你
keep you out of trouble
讓你不要出問題
Most likely to remain in this state
大部分可能就是維持在這種狀態
How to destroy this balance
那怎麼樣破壞這個平衡
a balance is to say
一個平衡就是說
immune system compromised
免疫系統被破壞
under certain conditions
某些狀況之下 生病
or take some immunosuppressants
或者服用一些免疫的抑制劑
or other reasons for your immune system to
或者其他原因 讓你的免疫系統
Decreased immune protection
免疫保護能力下降
At this time, cancer cells have a chance to win
這時候 癌細胞就有機會勝出
or the continued evolution of cancer cells
或者 癌細胞繼續的演化
Because your immune system is going to attack him
因為你免疫系統是要攻擊到他
killed by him
被他殺死就殺死了
If he survives, he will not be afraid of you
活下來的他就不害怕你
So he slowly and gradually changed
所以他就慢慢慢慢逐漸改變
This process may take a year or two, maybe ten or twenty years
這個過程可能是一年兩年 可能十年二十年
So in the end you have some cancer cells
所以最後呢 你就有一些癌細胞呢
After he's trained, he's less afraid of your immune system attacking.
他訓練出來 他就不太怕你的免疫系統攻擊了
He has the opportunity to be under the condition of immune cell attack
他就有機會在有免疫的細胞攻擊的條件之下
He was also able to grow a large tumor
他還能夠長出一個大的腫瘤
This is a clinical tumor
這個就是臨床上的腫瘤
this time you will see a doctor
這個時候你會去看醫生
So that is
所以 也就是說
You see those oncologists in the clinic
你看到臨床上那些癌症醫師
He faces very familiar problems
他面臨很極熟的問題
because all these cancer cells
因為所有這些癌細胞
He is already in such a state of shock
他都已經是這種深驚百戰
i'm so scared
我太怕了
Then the IC protection of your patient's immune system
那你這個病人的免疫系統的這個IC保
grow out to grow out
長出來才長出來
So you need immune drugs to control it
所以你要免疫藥物去控制它
Of course it's more difficult
當然就更困難了
So this is the problem we face clinically
所以這個是我們在臨床上面臨的問題
how to deal with these
怎麼樣去對付這些
The fighters of IC protection who have been shocked by the immune attack
已經對免疫攻擊深驚百戰的IC保的戰士
How to give this immune system again
怎麼樣再賦予這個免疫系統
Stronger ability to eliminate these IC protection
更強的消滅這些IC保的能力
This is the only way to control these
這樣才有機會去控制這些
Clinically these IC protection
臨床上的這些IC保
Then this is what I just mentioned
那這個就我剛剛提過這個
The Four Survival Ways of IC Bao
IC保的四者生存之道
Okay, let's give some more clinical examples
好,那這邊再舉一些臨床的例子
This is the treatment of colorectal cancer
這個是大腸癌的治療
This is not immunotherapy, this is traditional treatment
這不是免疫治療,這是傳統治療
surgery, radiation therapy, chemotherapy
手術,放射治療,化學治療
Then if you look at this A, B, C, D
那大家如果看這個A、B、C、D
The four types of patients
這四種型態的病人
A and C
A跟C
You see this tumor is very small
你看這腫瘤很小
Section 08 has not yet been violated
還沒有侵犯到08節
Therefore, this is usually classified as sweeping syndrome in pathological classification.
所以通常這個在病理分類就是掃起來症
It's probably fine to cut it off
切掉大概就沒事
Then that patient B and D
然後那個B跟D這個病人
It's red is a cancer cell
它這紅色是癌細胞
Not only in the original flavor but also violated the 08 section
不但在原味而且已經侵犯到這個08節了
Then to this 08 tube
然後到這08管
So these patients are classified as
所以這些病人在分類上面是講
This may be a pathological classification
這可能是病理分類
it may be more malignant
這可能是比較惡性的
Already violated tube 08 so probably transferred
已經侵犯08管 所以很可能是轉移的
The prognosis may be worse
的愈後可能比較不好
Then they counted a lot of treated cases
然後他們就是統計了非常非常多治療的病例
and then come to this conclusion
然後得到這個結論
Discover
發現
Originally this B
本來這個B
B this A this patient looks like a small
B這個A這個病人看起來像小小的
should be fine
應該會還不錯
It should be fine after recovery, but he is actually not well after recovery.
愈後應該還不錯 結果他愈後其實病不好
Then this D this patient
然後這個D這個病人
Looks like the red tumor has invaded the 08 section
看起來紅色腫瘤已經侵犯這08節了
Then maybe it was transferred, of course everyone said
然後可能是轉移了 大家當然講
That, what Teacher Tang just said, once this is invaded, the metastatic cancer may be difficult to treat
那個,唐老師剛剛講說,這個一旦侵犯了,轉移的癌症可能很難治療
But according to this patient, according to their statistics, this type of patient is not bad
可是這個病人看,就是他們統計,這一類病人,還不錯
The big big difference is the yellow cells
那一個很大很大的差別,是黃色的這些細胞
These are immune cells, especially T cells
這些是免疫細胞,尤其是T細胞
If this patient has a lot of 08 cells in the cancer tissue he removed
如果這個病人,他切下來的癌組織裡面,有比較多的08細胞
For example, patients C and D, no matter what treatment they receive, be it chemotherapy, radiotherapy, or surgery, they are less likely to relapse
比如說C跟D這個病人,他不管接受什麼治療,化療也好,放射治療也好,手術也好,他就比較不容易復發
But if he doesn't have these T cells, he will heal longer
可是如果他沒有這些T細胞,他愈後比較長
This article, this is a Review Paper, which summarizes many clinical cases
這一篇,這個是一個叫Review Paper,它是總結很多臨床的實際上的案例
Put forward a statement at that time, that is to say, in addition to the classification of these pathologies
提出一個當時的一個講述,就是說,除了這些病理上面的分類之外
People also take into account the classification of immunity
人家也把免疫的分類考慮進去
This way the prognosis for this cancer patient will be more accurate.
這樣子對這個癌症病人的預後才會更準確
This is the conclusion obtained in patients with colorectal cancer
這個是在大腸癌病人得到的結論
Even other cancers were later found to have similar conclusions
甚至後來發現其他的癌症也有類似的結論
That is to say
也就是說
Some patients have cancer because more T cells enter the lung
有些病人他的癌症就是比較多T細胞進倫
This kind of patient is easier
這種病人就是比較容易好
No matter what you do to treat him, it will be easier.
不管你什麼治療他都比較容易好
next to ask
接下來要問
Why do these patients have more T cells
為什麼這些病人有比較多T細胞進倫
I don't know
我就不知道
This is what we need to understand in our research
這個就是我們在研究上面需要去理解的問題
The next challenge of positive treatment is to say
接下來正治療的挑戰就是說
Why Only a Few Patients Have Better T Cells
為什麼只有少數病人有比較好的T細胞胞
if not
如果沒有的話
Is there any way you can make it happen
你有沒有辦法讓它產生呢
That's what everyone said at the beginning
那剛剛一開始大家會講過
we generate
我們產生的
He's phagocytosis, remember, phagocytosis
他是吞,記不記得,是吞式細胞
after swallowing bacteria
吞式細菌之後
Bacterial antigens carried
攜帶的細菌的抗原
presented to the T cell, which produces
呈現給T細胞,讓它產生的
Right, so we're actually progressing our immunology
對,所以我們其實我們的免疫學的進展
We know how T cells are produced, we know that
我們知道T細胞如何產生,這我們是知道的
Is there a way for us to use this knowledge to train
那我們有沒有辦法利用這樣的知識去訓練
This, the human immune system
這個,人體的免疫系統
Generate T cells that fight cancer
產生對抗癌症的T細胞
The biggest difficulty is that we don't know much about our enemies
最大的困難就是,我們不太知道我們的敵人
His cells are so similar to our cells
他的跟我們的細胞,因為太像了
Cancer cells, in the eyes of T cells
癌細胞,在T細胞眼中
It's almost the same as a normal cell
他幾乎跟正常的細胞是一樣的
his entire genetic makeup
他在整個的基因的組成
his protein
他的產生的蛋白
almost very very similar to
幾乎非常非常類似
So basically we don't react to him.
所以大致上我們對他是不反應的
So we have to find a way to stimulate
所以我們要找到一個方法能夠去刺激
to cancer, especially to his tumor antigens
對癌症,尤其是對他的腫瘤抗原
professional reminder, save
專業性的提醒,保存
then this may be now
那這個可能就是現在
May be applied to current immunization profiles
可能會應用到現在的免疫資料
That
那
tumor microenvironment
腫瘤微環境
We now see such a large tumor
我們現在看到那麼一大顆腫瘤
a tumor
一個tumors
In fact, there are not only IC packets in this tumor.
其實這個腫瘤裡面不是只有IC包
it has a lot
它有很多的
composition
組成
It's all about fighting the immune system
都是來對抗免疫系統的
so I call it
所以我把它稱之為
it this
它這個
Tumor microcircle is tumor micro environment
腫瘤微環就是tumor micro environment
It is actually built by the IC package
它其實是IC包所構築的
A well-balanced defense bag
兼顧的防禦包裏
who to defend
防禦誰
defend your body's immune system
防禦你身體的免疫系統
like it has a chance of surviving
像它才有機會可以生存起來
That's swollen
那這個就是腫
its mechanism
這個它的機制
This is a kind
這個就是一個種類
everyone can see
大家可以看到
These gray ones are IC bags
這些灰色的是IC包
There are many cells in there
那裡面還有很多細胞
Blood vessel
血管
Because the IC package grows it needs blood vessels
因為IC包生長它需要血管
supply it with nutrients and oxygen
供應它養分跟氧氣
Then you see there are many immune cells
那你看還有很多免疫細胞
There are also T cells
T細胞也有啊
These antigen presenting cells, these
這些抗原呈現細胞啊這些
The tumor micro environment just mentioned
剛剛講的tumor micro environment
both
都有啊
a lot of
很多
So after you take that cancer out you give him a test
所以你把那個癌症拿出來之後你給他去做檢查
Anyway, there are a lot of immune cells in it
反正裡面很多免疫細胞
So that's weird. Is this immunity to attack cancer?
所以這很奇怪 那這免疫是要攻擊癌症的嗎
so what
那怎麼
he doesn't play his part
他不發揮他的作用
It turns out that cancer just said that cancer should be able to
原來 癌症 剛剛講說癌症要能夠
try to survive it evolve some different mechanics
試著生存哦 就它演化出一些不同的機制
It actually removes those cancer cells
它其實就將那些癌細胞
Uh, these immune cells are going to attack it
呃 這些免疫細胞 要來攻擊它
But once it gets to the cancer cell, he trains it
可是一旦到癌細胞之後 他就訓練它
Turn it from an enemy who attacked it to a good friend
將它 從原來攻擊它的敵人 變成它的好朋友
So you look at these inside the tumor
所以你看這一些 在腫瘤裡面的這些
Immune Cells
免疫細胞
In fact, it becomes an immune suppressor cell.
其實都變成一個免疫的抑制細胞
Its function is to suppress immune cells
它的功用是來抑制免疫細胞的
So it uses the hair of the son to attack the shield of the son
所以它 以子之毛 攻子之盾
It trains these immune cells, cancer cells to train these immune cells
它訓練這些免疫細胞 癌細胞 去訓練這些免疫細胞
make it able to deal with
讓它能夠對付
Attack of the body's other immune cells
身體的其他免疫細胞的攻擊
very strong
很壯麵吧
So these we call
所以這些呢我們稱之為
Inmute Suppressor Sales Immunosuppressive cells
Inmute Suppressor Sales 免疫抑制細胞
its essence is
它的本質呢都是
I just said that hematopoietic stem cells are trained
剛剛講造血幹細胞訓練出來的
These phagocytes
這些吞噬細胞
But cancer cells have the ability to train it to
可是癌細胞就是有能力將它訓練成
immunosuppressive cells
免疫抑制細胞
Then it uses a different mechanism
然後它用不同的機制
I wonder if any of you are interested in this?
那我想這個你們大家有沒有興趣
Many different ABCDEFG
很多不同ABCDEFG
various mechanisms
各種不同的機制
to suppress it
去抑制它
OK
OK
That
那
So here I will use cartoon clothes to introduce
所以這邊就用卡通服來介紹一下
This is antigenic laminarity
這個齁是抗原層性
I just said that the phagocytic cells look like this
剛剛講這吞噬細胞長這樣
Then if you encounter this cancer cell
那如果碰到這個癌細胞
it's the same it will eat it up
它也是一樣啊會把它吞噬掉
Useless after devouring
吞噬之後沒用
instead it becomes
它反而是變成
suppressor cells
抑制型細胞
Suppressor Suppressor Antigenic Laminar Cells
那抑制型的抑制型的抗原層性細胞
It presents to T cells
它呈現給T細胞
T cells become wet energy
T細胞變成濕能
Non-functioning air bag
沒有功能的提氣包
It's much different from just now
跟剛剛這個差很多
After touching bacteria, it looks like this
碰到細菌之後,它是變成這個樣子
it becomes this
它是變成這種
very empty phagocytes
很空無有力的吞噬細胞
this won't work
這個就不太行
Then this is an activated air bag, this is a non-functional air bag
那這個是活化的提氣包,這個是一個沒有功能的提氣包
So there are different types of air bags
所以提氣包有不同種類
White blood cells can disable your gas bag
白細胞就讓你的提氣包失去功能
good
好
Now we think, what we now call the rapid development of immunotherapy
那現在我們就想,我們現在所謂免疫治療的突飛
Is there a way we can make these defunct air bags
我們有沒有辦法讓這些已經失去功能的提氣包
restore its functionality
重新恢復它的功能
A rejuvenated gas bag, if it can recognize cancer cells
重新恢復功能的提氣包,如果它能夠辨識癌細胞的話
Is there a way to kill cancer cells
有沒有辦法去殺死癌細胞
So this is what we know recently
那這個就是我們最近知道的這些
Major advances in immunotherapy
免疫治療的重大進展
The answer, of course, is yes, at least for some patients.
那答案當然是,至少對某些病人是可以的
Then its practice is the past few years
那它的做法,就是這幾年的
Some breakthroughs, and then introduce these methods
一些突破,接下來就介紹這些做法
It has some effect, that is, it uses active immunotherapy
它有一些作用,就是用主動式的免疫療法
I just talked about the back-kinetic and active-kinetic, that is, your body produces these T cells
剛剛講背動式跟主動式,就是你身體去產生這些T細胞
But the T cells have been disabled and have no function, right?
可是T細胞已經失能了,沒有功能了,對不對?
A simple solution is fine, if I know that this T cell is very important
簡單辦法就好,如果說我知道這個T細胞很重要
Then I am like T cells that get the name of the city management and cultivate a large number of them.
那我就像T細胞拿到市管裡面培養名,大量的去培養
Enter after training
培養之後再打進去
This we call T cell infusion therapy
這個我們稱之為T細胞輸入療法
In this case, you can see that its function is to cut out the tumor
這個的話,你看它作用在,就是你將這腫瘤塊切出來
These T cells inside, it will be cultivated in the future
裡面的這些T細胞,它將來培養
After being cultivated, it goes to the screening
培養之後,它就要去篩選
Those T cells that kill cancer cells
那一些會殺死癌細胞的T細胞
These are added now, that is, the T cells can kill cancer cells
這些現在講加好的,就是這個T細胞,會殺死癌細胞
Then it will be cultivated in large numbers in the future
然後它將來大量的培養
mass culture, of course it can be deactivated
大量培養,當然可以去活化它
beat it into this ward
再把它打進去這個病房
This we call T cell infusion therapy
這個我們稱之為T細胞輸入療法
It's a passive immunity
這是一種被動式的免疫
very effective
非常有效
for certain cancers
對某些癌症
Now this we call Tumor Influent Tritin Lymphocyte
現在這個我們叫Tumor Influent Tritin Lymphocyte
Lymphocytes in tumors
翻譯成腫瘤裡面的淋巴細胞
This Cartysil
這Cartysil
This is the T cell of Chimeric Antigen Receptor
這是Chimeric Antigen Receptor的T細胞
These are essentially T cells
這些本質都是T細胞
It just makes it recognize different types of antigens
它只是讓它辨識的抗原種類不同
Cartysil is currently very red
Cartysil是目前非常紅的
you see it for some cancers
你看它對某些癌症
Especially the treatment rate of hematologic lymphoma and blood cancer
尤其是血液淋巴癌血癌的治療率
hundred percent
百分之百
But the past is hard to imagine
可是過去是很難想像的
but it needs to be
但是它需要就是
every cancer patient
每個癌症病人
To make its own Cartysil
要做它自己的Cartysil
So the fee will probably be considerable
所以發費大概會很可觀
another big problem
另外一個很大的問題
That is, how long will the effect last?
就是說這個療效能夠維持多久
This needs to be observed again
這個還要再觀察
But these patients were not
但是這些病人過去是沒有
other treatment opportunities
其他治療機會的
Then use this T cell infusion therapy now
那現在用這種T細胞輸入療法
can you
可以呢
Almost all cancer cells are under control
幾乎就將癌細胞全部控制住
So this is a really big breakthrough
所以這個是一個非常大的突破
But what about this infusion therapy?
但是這個輸入療法呢
with considerable side effects
也伴隨著相當程度的副作用
Some of them even caused the death of the patient
那有一些甚至會造成病人的死亡
Because imagine this T cell
因為想像這個T細胞
hit so many activated T cells
打那麼多活化的T細胞
Many found that it has similarities with normal cells
很多發現它有跟正常細胞
also affects normal cells
也會波及正常細胞
affect normal cells
波及正常細胞
the inflammatory response
造成的這個發炎反應
serious death of the patient
嚴重的造成病人的死亡
So any immune person who is effective
所以任何的免疫者如果有效
In fact, it will be accompanied by different degrees of side effects
其實都會伴隨不同程度的副作用
immune-related side effects
免疫相關的副作用
some autoimmune diseases
有一些是自體免疫病
so we have to learn
所以我們要學習
How to control our immune system
怎麼樣去控制我們的免疫系統
let it work to its advantage
讓它能夠發揮它的好處
but avoid its disadvantages
但是避免它的壞處
This is one of the future for this immunotherapy
這是未來的這個免疫治療的一個
place to learn
需要學習的地方
Then there's the other thing, the immune checkpoint elements.
那另外呢 就是免疫檢查哨分子
Then this hall award was founded in Taiwan
那這個堂獎 就台灣創辦的
exist
在
At that time in 2014
在那個2014年的時候
Awarded to these two winners
就頒獎給這兩位得獎人
One named James Ellison
一個叫James Ellison
U.S.
美國
because it is called
因為叫做
Motojuku
本宿佑
in Japan
在日本
Then they invented separately
那他們分別發明
Discover
發現
Two different immune checkpoint molecules
兩種不同的免疫檢查哨分子
One is called CTLA4
一個叫CTLA4
One is called PD1
一個叫PD1
How does it work?
那它原理呢
I will tell you with cartoon pictures
我就跟大家用卡通圖跟大家說
This T cell private T cell
這個T細胞 私能的T細胞
just said just said
剛剛講 剛剛講到
ICB has various
ICB有各種不同的
immunotherapeutic
免疫治方式的
one of them
其中一種
It's this immune checkpoint molecule.
就是這種免疫檢查哨分子
it makes this
它讓這個
Well
呃
Performance such as this PDL1
表現比如說這個PDL1
It will bind to the PD1 on the T cell
會跟T細胞上面這個PD1結合
After the combination, the TG package loses its function
結合之後,在TG包就失去功能
So it's called an immune checkpoint, and that's it.
所以叫免疫檢查哨,就是這樣
Will the TG package function
意志的TG包功能
It manifests itself on the immune will cells
它會表現在免疫意志細胞上面
also manifested on the returning cells
也會表現在還細胞上面
So it's easy, when you understand the principle
所以這樣就很容易啦,當你了解這個原理的時候
I just thought, what if, with this combination, I will make the TG package lose its function
就想,如果呢,這樣子的結合,我讓TG包失去功能
I'll break its bond
我就破壞它的結合啊
So they invented these two antibody drugs
所以他們發明這兩種抗體藥物
Inject antibody drugs into
注射抗體藥物進去
What about antibodies, bind to it
抗體呢,跟它結合
unite with it, uh, separate it
跟它結合,欸,把它分開
The TG package will no longer be affected by these two molecules at this time
TG包這個時候就不再受到這兩個分子
regulation of elicited immune volition
所引發的免疫意志的調控
Then this TG package didn't seem to work
然後這個TG包本來看起來不太行的
seems to restore its functionality
好像恢復它的功能
Is there any chance to restore the function of TG package like this?
這樣恢復功能的TG包,有沒有機會呢
to kill the patient's tumor
去殺死這個病人的腫瘤
as it is
就它怎麼樣
Principle of action
作用原理
So the patient is injected with this antibody
所以病人就打這個這種抗體進去
Look at this example, these two articles are in
你看這個例子,這兩篇是在
Published in well-known medical journals for 12 years
12年發表在很著名的醫學期刊
The New England Journal
叫《新英格蘭期刊》
introduce the story
介紹這個故事
Let me give you a few examples. This is lung metastasis before treatment.
這舉幾個例子給大家看,這是治療前的肺轉移
Administration This is PD1
給藥這個是PD1
this healing machine
這個醫治機
after 90 days
90天之後
This is liver metastases
這是肝轉移
And then here are the T cells in the tumor before treatment
然後這是治療前的腫瘤裡面的T細胞
Black
黑色的
few
少少的
after treatment you see
治療之後,你看
Breath puts a lot of increase
氣息把大量的增加
may restore it to function
可能會恢復它功能
this is
這個是
this is skin
這個是皮膚的
menanoma, melanoma
menanoma,黑色素瘤
Before treatment
治療前
the tumor
腫瘤
After treatment
治療後
Then I saw the large number of T cells
然後又看到這T細胞大量的症
So it looks like the effective treatment seems to be that the T cells
所以看起來有效的治療 好像這T細胞
It restores the function of T cells after treatment
它這治療之後會恢復這T細胞的功能
Then compare it with chemotherapy
然後呢它跟化學治療去做比較
This is an antibody for NTPD1, ​​of course this is
這個是NTPD1的抗體 那這個當然是
This is a relatively short experiment, probably more than a year
這個是比較短的實驗 大概是一年多
to this melanin flow
對這種黑色素流
The over-2 survival rate of this antibody
這個抗體的over-2的存活率
to about 16 months
到16個月左右
yes win this chemistry this chemotherapy
是贏這個化學 這種化學治療
but more then
但是更 然後
this kind of
這樣子的這種
Immunological check check acceptor molecule
免疫檢查 檢查 受分子
Not just effective against one type of cancer
不只是對一種癌症有效
It has different effects on lung cancer melanoma
它對不同肺癌 黑色素癌
Kidney cancer Stomach cancer Head kidney cancer
腎 臟癌 胃癌 頭腎癌
have varying degrees of effect, for example, on lung cancer
都有不同程度的效果 比如說對肺癌
This study is 23%
這個研究是23%
23% of patients
23%的病人
Responsive
有反應
The best is black is 5% to 30%
最好的是黑色是5%到30%
The other about 10%
那其他大概有10幾%
Don't forget that these are patients with no means of treatment in the past
不要忘記這些都是過去沒有辦法治療的病人
So now we can achieve a success rate that is almost close to 20%
所以現在我們可以達到幾乎差不多接近20%左右的成功率
Using such an immune test for small molecules
用這樣子的免疫檢查少分子
What he is most concerned about is how long his curative effect can last.
那他最關心的就是他的療效可以維持多久
If he only lives two years, it doesn't seem like enough.
如果他只活兩年好像還不太夠
you want to heal him
你希望能夠把他治好
is there any chance
有沒有機會
Then this clinical trial
那這個臨床試驗
this is not a clinical trial
這不是一個臨床試驗
This is because the CTOA4 immune test was detected earlier
這個是因為CTOA4這個免疫檢查出來比較早
So he's been a patient long enough now
所以他現在已經有足夠久的病人
end up over 10 years
最終超過10年
Then recently they reorganized and published the results
那最近他們把這個結果重新在整理發表
wait a minute
那等一下看
This is the more than 1000 people
這個就是這1000多位
Nearly 2,000 of these patients
接近2000位的這個病人
how to read it here
那這邊怎麼讀
This is over 25
這個是over 25
his survival rate
他的存活率
That is, if you die, he will decrease
就是你如果死亡他就減少
Then this is the time, from the beginning, all the patients are alive
那這個就是時間,從一開始,所有的病人都活著
And then at one year, at 12 months, about half of the patients are still alive
然後到一年的時候,12個月的時候,大概剩下一半的病人還活著
Then these are the transferred melanin materials, which were almost difficult to treat in the past
那這些都是轉移的黑色素料,過去是幾乎很難治療的
In two years, there will be a little more than 20% left
到兩年的時候,剩下比20%多一點點
There are probably more than 2 out of 10 people who can survive
10個人裡面大概還有2點多個可以活下來
But you only need to survive for two years, with this medicine for two years, it seems that it will be fine
可是你只要撐過兩年,用這個藥撐過兩年,好像它就好了
it just keeps dying without these
它就沒有這些繼續死亡
Look at it for three years, four years, five years until ten years
你看它三年、四年、五年一直到十年
but maintain this cove
但是維持這個科夫
So this group of patients, the lucky ones, seems to be cured
所以這一群病人,幸運的病人,好像就被治癒了
So I just spoke, as if cured, over ten years
所以我剛剛講說,好像被治癒了,超過十年
will really take longer
就會真的至於要時間更久
Can be verified but should be very organic
可以證實 但是應該是很有機
even if not cured
即使沒有治好
Possibly, he's also been held in check by the immune system for a long time.
可能呢 他也被免疫系統長期的控制住
So at least this is a very
所以至少呢 這個是一個非常
In the field of cancer treatment is a
在癌症治療領域裡面是一個
almost unheard of
幾乎過去不曾聽說過的
A cancer patient can live for such a long time
一個癌症病人可以這麼長期的
so many patients
這麼多病人
If it is 1861 bit 20%
如果是1861位 20%
that is there
那就是有
More than 300 fast 400 people
300多快400個人
But it's a pretty impressive number
可是這是一個相當可觀的數字
If many patients
如果說很多病人
Other cancer patients have the same effect
其他癌症病人也有同樣的療效
that is a very generous
那就是一個非常大度
that looks now
那現在看起來
The effect of PD1
PD1的效果
better than this CDLF
比這個CDLF還更好
So it has the potential to be better curative
所以它有可能會得到更好的療效
Is that true for other types of cancer?
那是不是對其他種類癌症
It also has such a good effect
也有這麼好的療效
depends on
就要看
After that tracked treatment
之後的那個追蹤的治療
then this is me
那這個是我
Ask the student to sort it out
請那個學生整理了一下
These drugs are available in Taiwan
在台灣可以用到的這些藥物
This PD1 monoclonal antibody
這個PD1的單株抗體
Pembro Zilume
Pembro Zilume
This is another PD1 antibody
這個是另外一種PD1抗體
This is the CT2F4 antibody
這是CT2F4抗體
different name
不同的名字
This word is per kilogram
這個話是每公斤
two fate monsters
兩個命運怪
It is about 50 100 for a patient weighing 50 kg
就是在50公斤的病人大概用50 100
once every three weeks
三個禮拜打一次
260,000 once
一次 26萬
so the price is very good
所以價錢非常可觀
if you play for a year
你如果打一年
4000000
400萬
then this drug
然後這一個藥物
Because it hits more frequently than
因為它打的比頻率更高
see 900
看到900
In this case, the most frequent frequency may be 300
這個的話最頻率的可能要300
So it's expensive anyway
所以反正都是很貴的
And then only about 20%
然後又只有大概20%
efficient
有效
may also be responsible
可能還有負責
But you look like you might be called Q
但是呢 你有像可能叫Q
It's not the same as in the past. In the past, you might extend
跟過去不太一樣 過去呢 你可能延長
This may be called the global
這個有可能叫全域
So there is a big problem here
所以這邊呢 有一個很大問題
How about us because it costs a lot and needs to be traded to varying degrees
我們怎麼樣 因為花費很高嘛 而且要貿不同程度的
This side effect, is there a way to screen out these potentially effective
這副作用 有沒有辦法去篩選出這些可能有效的
20% of the patients, then I just treat those patients
20%的病人 那我只治療那些病人就好了
The other 8% doesn't work anyway, so don't waste the money
其他的百分之八 反正沒效 就不用浪費這個錢
So this is currently a very important research figure called BioMark
所以這個是目前一個很重要的研究人物 叫做BioMark
Biomarker How to find patients who may be effective
生物標記 怎麼樣去找到可能有效的病人
And then treat these patients, wait a minute, I just had a breakthrough last month.
然後治療這些病人 等一下我來 最近上個月才有突破
So I'm going to make that slide again today
所以我今天再把那個投影片做出來
And now, several challenges, expensive
而現在呢 幾個挑戰 價錢昂貴
Too expensive but help
太貴了 可是救命哦
And the second one, there are only a few patients left because 20% is not bad
那第二呢 只剩少數的病人 因為20%雖然不錯
The price is very low, yes
天價很低啦 對
5 people only one
5個人只有一個
But for him, his 20% is very useful
可是對他來對他這20%是很有用
We have a way to develop more effective
我們有辦法研發出更有效的
From 20% and up
從20%再往上升
The third is that it is inevitable that
第三就是不可避免的可能會
With immune-related side effects
伴隨免疫相關的副作用
serious will be serious
嚴重的會很嚴重
In this regard, further research and development
這方面也是要做進一步的研發
Next, I will tell him some of the decisions about immunotherapy.
接下來我就跟他講決定免疫治療的一些
You just saw that example
大家剛剛看那個例子
patients with colorectal cancer receiving traditional treatment
就是大腸癌病人接受傳統治療
If he has T cells
如果他有T細胞進論
Colorectal cancer is more likely to be better
的大腸癌比較容易好
In fact, it was found that the immune
其實發現免疫者也是
Why in 20% of patients
為什麼在20%的病人
who works and who doesn't
哪些人有效哪些人沒效
You see, this is a patient who doesn't respond to treatment.
你看這個是一個治療沒效的病人
Before treatment After treatment This is his tumor
治療前 治療後 這個是他腫瘤
This is to see that CDS is a kind of T cell
這邊是看CDS是一種T細胞
you can't see the black one
你看不到那個黑色的
A little bit here, only a little bit after treatment
這邊少數一點點 治療後也只有一點點
So this patient is nothing small
所以這個病人沒什麼小
But look at the patient who was treated effectively
可是你看那個治療有效的病人
Some T cells were already present before treatment
治療前就已經存在一些T細胞
more after treatment
治療後更多
Then the tumor was under his control
然後這個腫瘤就被他控制住
So they found that for the same reason
所以他們發現 同樣的原因
If the patient
如果這個病人
He already had these T cells in
他本來就有這些T細胞在
It's just that he lost the function of T cells called wet energy.
只是他失去功能 叫濕能的T細胞
I didn't just say that
我剛剛不是講的
put that brake on
把那個煞車
Get rid of the reason that made him burn into wet energy
把那個讓他燒成濕能的原因把它拿掉
The T cells are reactivated
這T細胞就重新活化
But if you don't have this kind of T cells
可是你如果本身就沒有這種T細胞
Then you don't suck
那你就沒吸腸了
It's useless for you to take medicine now
你現在打著藥也沒用
you don't have
你根本就沒有
so it's going to be a challenge
所以這會是一個挑戰
how to make this patient
怎麼樣去製造這個病人
The original non-existing system package to fight cancer
原來不存在的對抗癌症的體系包
In this way, more patients can be benefited
那這樣的話可以造福更多的病人
The other 80% of patients
另外80%的病人
This is the direction of future research and development
這是未來研發的方向
Oh, that's what I just said
那這個喔是剛剛講過
It was a report that came out last month.
就是上個月還出來的一個報告
This report is actually quite an astonishing one.
這個報告其實真的是相當驚人的一個報告
What I just talked about is melanin flow
剛剛講的都是黑色素流
Melanin flow is not so much in Taiwan
黑色素流台灣並不是那麼多
Our concern is lung cancer
我們關心的是肺癌
liver cancer
肝癌
colorectal cancer deer cancer
大腸癌 鹿癌
These are the most common
這些才是最常見的
Are these effective against these common cancers?
那到底這些對這些常見的癌症有沒有效
Well, they are the findings of this study
那他們喔就是這個研究是發現
There is something we call tumor heart anticancer
有一些我們稱之為腫瘤心抗癌
Called Neoantigen
叫Neoantigen
just mentioned
剛剛有提到過
Cancer cells are different from normal cells
就是癌細胞跟正常細胞是有區隔的
because it keeps mutating
因為它一直在發生突變
Mutations are the guarantee of its survival
突變是它生存的發保
It was born because of a mutation so it was able to
它生 它因為突變 所以它才能夠
Blaming itself for survival, so it keeps accumulating these different mutations
自責生存,所以它就一直累積這些不同突變
What about some of these mutations, which can cause tumor heart antigen
那這些有些突變呢,會造成腫瘤心抗原
Then they found that some cancers
那他們發現,就有一些癌症
Because of gene repair, our body cells have a repair function
因為基因修復,我們身體細胞有一個修復功能
Then when you mutate, we'll have some
那你發生突變的時候,我們會有一些
Some efficiencies will fix it back
一些效率會把它修正回來
But some cancer cells have lost this correction function
可是有一些癌細胞失去了這一個修正的功能
This is a tumor where the body's genetic repair is defective
這是身體的基因修復缺陷的腫瘤
because it cannot correct these mutations
因為它不能夠修正這些突變
So of course it will accumulate more mutations
所以它當然就會累積比較多的突變
tumor heart antigen
也就是比較多的腫瘤心抗原
That antigen is what produces T cells
那抗原是產生 T細胞的
necessary molecule
必要的分子
So the researcher thinks that if the tumor
所以這研究者就認為說,如果這個腫瘤
have more antigens
有更多的抗原
more of this
更多的這個
Newtation
Newtation
So, will this become easier for
所以呢會不會這種變成更容易對
You've got to work too, that's their hypothesis
你也一直要有效,這是他們的假說
So they are screening
所以他們就是篩選
inside the tumor
腫瘤裡面
Tumors with defects in gene repair
具有在基因修復缺陷的腫瘤
only treat this patient
只治療這種病人
see if it responds better
看看它反應效果會不會更好
At this time it is not only doing
這個時候它就不只是在做
Just now that melanoma it did across
剛才那個黑色素瘤 它做的橫跨
12 different types of cancer
12種不同的癌症
86 patients with genetic autumn blood
具有基因秋血 86 個病人
The number of patients is not that many 86 patients
病人的數目還沒有很多 86個病人
This includes the most common
這裡面包括最常見的
colorectal cancer
大腸癌
This is pancreatic cancer
這個是胰臟癌
this
這個
There is still hope, there is no lung cancer here
還有期待 這邊沒有 lung cancer
this is stomach cancer
這個是胃癌
12 Different Gene Repair Defective Cancers
12種不同的基因修復缺陷的癌症
treatment effect
治療效果
this is
這個是
belly hundred is
腹一百就是
Eliminate all. It originally treats those that are not eliminated as zero.
全部消掉 它本來把那個都不消的當作零
The tumor turned out to be five centimeters
腫瘤原來是五公分
You are still five centimeters after treatment, that is to maintain the same
你治療之後還是五公分 那就是維持持平
it doesn't last long
它也不長 也不消
But if it becomes zero
可是如果變成零
If there is nothing, then this one is over here
消到沒有 那這個在這邊
This is negative 100, all disappeared
這個就負100,全部都消失了
From here, patients like these are
從這邊做出來,像這幾個病人就是
Not only is it useless after treatment, but he continues to grow
他不但治療之後沒什麼用,他還是繼續長
But as you can see, useful patients
可是你可以看到,有用的病人
It has reached 50%
已經達到50%了
From just a few dozen, now to 50%
從剛剛這10幾,現在到50%
The only thing he did was to sift through those
他唯一做的,就是去篩選那一些
Tumors with gene repair tangents
有基因修復切線的腫瘤
That will significantly increase his healing effect.
那就顯著提高他治療效果
The longest of these has been almost three years
這些最長已經到快三年了
So tell us here, one of the
所以這邊就告訴我們,其中一個
effective against immune persons, that is
對免疫者有效,就是說
This tumor, it has many genetic mutations
這個腫瘤,它有很多的基因突變
Mutations in this gene create new antigens
這基因突變,就製造出新的抗原
new antigen
新的抗原,就是
May stimulate more somatic cells
可能刺激更多的體細胞
worked for him, so their study actually found
對他有作用,所以他們這研究其實也發現了
After treatment, these systemic cells that are specialized for tumor heart antigens were found to increase
治療之後發現這些對腫瘤心抗原具有專醫性的體系胞增加
This tells the story
這一點都告訴我們這件故事
Tumors are most afraid of systemic cells
腫瘤最怕就是體系胞
Tumors with more genetic mutations
那些基因突變越多的腫瘤
Although it can apply this immune system attack
雖然它能夠適用這個免疫系統攻擊
but
但是呢
It is also more susceptible to systemic attack
它也更容易被體系胞攻擊
Now if say
那現在如果說
Clinicians
臨床醫師
That's actually been approved
那這個其實已經被核准
This is a treatment with a rare
這個是治療上面有一個很少見的
that is
就是說
It has been approved that is to say as long as
它已經核准就是說只要
patients with metastatic cancer
轉移癌病人
patients with gene repair tangents
又具有基因修復切線的病人
can be treated with this drug
都可以用這種藥物去做治療
Then Taiwan should not have entered yet.
那台灣現在應該還沒有進來
But I reckon this should be fast
但是我估計這應該會很快
will be approved in Taiwan
會在台灣會核准
that's right
那這個對對對
Many patients with metastatic cancer are of course a great boon.
許多的轉移癌病人當然就很大的福音了哦
If you have cancer, it happens to be the tangent of this kind of gene repair
如果說你癌症那正好也是這種基因修復切線
then just
那就就
for this immunotherapy
對這種免疫治療的
The success rate will be significantly improved
成功率就會顯著的提高
Then this is some basic research that can help some clinical progress
那這個就是一些基礎研究可以幫忙臨床的一些進展
next last little time
接下來最後一點點時間
now let's do
現在我們先去做
that just said this
那剛剛講過這一些
whether gene repair defect
不管是基因修復缺陷
You actually rely on the T cells that your patient originally had.
你其實靠的都是自己病人原來有的T細胞
If the patient has no T cells
如果病人他沒有T細胞
Then you fight these current immune will machines
那你打這些現在的這些免疫意志機
it's useless
其實就沒什麼用
but we said
但我們講過就是
that triggers a T cell response
那個要引發T細胞反應
We actually have a lot of experience in the past
我們過去其實有非常多的經驗
Ability we know how to elicit a good T cell response
能力我們知道怎麼樣去引發一個好的T細胞反應
phagocytic activated phagocytes
就是那個吞噬細胞活化型的吞噬細胞
to present antigen
要呈現抗原
costimulatory molecule
有抗聯益共同刺激分子
Cytokines
有細胞激素
Like this one triggers a nice T cell response
像他這個引發一個很好的T細胞反應
So we are simulating
所以我們就是模擬
works like this
像這樣的作用
So we use the method of doing
所以我們用做的方法
radioimmunotherapy
就是利用放射免疫治療
go find this cancer
去找這個癌症
destroy it
破壞它
Didn't I just say that there are many cotton liquid lipid cells in it?
剛才不是講過裡面有很多棉液脂細胞
I can't kill tumor cells
我不能殺腫瘤細胞
Also kills cotton lipocytes
也殺棉液脂細胞
break down his entire fortress
把他整個 把他兼顧的堡壘打破
At this time, the cancer cells released
這個時候這個癌細胞釋放
He will also release this tumor antigen
他也會釋放這種瘤抗原出來
What about after his whole antigen is released?
他整個抗原釋放出來之後呢
Then you use immune drugs to deactivate the cells
你再用免疫藥物去活化提細胞
Finally hope that these T cells
最後希望這些T細胞
It can not only treat the cancer of the original stomach
不但能夠治療原胃的癌症
And he can use what he just said
而且他可以透過剛剛講過
the lymphatic system blood circulatory system
這個淋巴系統血液循環系統
to find those who hide somewhere
去找到那些不曉得躲在什麼地方的
not yet visible to the naked eye
肉眼還不可見的
I can't see that CT yet.
那個CT還見不到的
metastatic cancer
轉移癌
control it
控制它
or make peace with it
或者跟它和平共處
or just kill it
或者就消滅它
This is the principle of the whole treatment
這個就是整個治療的原理
we designed the animal model
我們就設計了動物模式
Make a big factory to come to the cell
打大廠來細胞
day zero fight
第零天打
To simulate a large factory to dry transfer
為了模擬大廠來乾轉移
we hit it to this leather stick
我們把它打到這個皮杖
it will transfer to dry
它會轉移到乾
wait till it grows
等到它總有長大
about 14 days later
大概14天之後
This original position has been hit
這個原位已經打到
more than 1 cm
再超過1公分
Metastatic cancer at this time
這個時候的轉移癌
eyes can't see yet
眼睛還看不到
But in a microscope like you can see
但在顯微鏡像你可以看到
this
這個
here
這裡
here are all these
這裡都有這些
we treat
我們治療
Only treat the cancer in situ
只治療這個原位的癌症
we only treat this
我們只治療這個
14 days old swollen face in situ
原位的14天大腫臉
Let's pretend we don't see the metastatic cancer
那個轉移癌症我們就假裝看不到
The main purpose is to
主要目的就是
Is there a way we can treat this
我們有沒有辦法在治療這個
carcinoma in situ
原位癌的時候
Simultaneous immune response
同時引發免疫反應
Of course the immune cells
當然這個免疫細胞
attack the cancer cells that have metastasized
是攻擊那些轉移出去的癌細胞
This is what we designed first
這是我們先設計的目的
Let's design a few groups
我們就設計幾組
a group does not treat it
一組就不治療它
when compared
當對照
One group only received radiation therapy
一組只做放射治療
One group only received immunotherapy and cell-based therapy
一組只做免疫治療 細胞基礎治療
The other group is radiation plus immunotherapy.
那另外一組就是放射加免疫治療
Its principle is to hope to generate new system cells
它原理是希望能夠產生新的體系胞出來
This is a control for carcinoma in situ
這個就是對原位癌的一個對照做化
This one does not treat it from day 1 we start treatment on day 14
這個不治療 它從第1 我們在14天開始治療
At this time, it is about 100 to 200 cubic meters.
這個時候大概就100到200個這個立方 黎米
Then when it is not treated, it continues to grow, and it grows here in 20 days
然後不治療的時候 它持續長大 到20幾天的時候長大到這裡
Any bigger and we'll kill
再大一點 我們就要殺掉
This is cellular immunotherapy itself, radiation therapy
這個是細胞免疫治療本身 放射治療
Radiation therapy alone, or immunotherapy alone, doesn't work very well.
光只靠放射治療 或者免疫治療本身 效果都不太好
It can delay its growth but still long
它可以延遲它生長 但是還是長
But if you combine these two treatments, the flow will disappear as soon as you see it
可是你如果合併這兩種治療 你一看它種流就消失
And not only for this transfer, but also for the transfer in the liver
而且不但對這個轉移 這個是對肝臟裡面的轉移
this is no treatment
這是不治療
this is radiation therapy
這是放射治療
this is immunotherapy
這是免疫治療
Although immunotherapy seems to be less effective than radiotherapy for the original taste
免疫治療雖然對原味來的效果看起來比放射治療差
But it is better for cancer treatment and effect
可是它的對轉醫癌和效果是比較好
Most notably, this combined treatment
最明顯的還是這個合併治療
another pattern
另外一個模式
Then after you treat this is no treatment
然後你治療之後這個是沒有治療
Radiation therapy is to look at the T cells
放射治療在裡面是看那個T細胞
T cells in the tumor
腫瘤部的T細胞
You can see more about this seventy-eighty-seventy treatment
這個七八七十治療你可以看得比較多的
Combination therapy
最多是合併治療
secret numb
祕密麻麻的
T cell responses following treatment
治療之後有所產生的T細胞反應
Another model is the spontaneous breast cancer model
另外一個模式是用自發性的乳癌模式
Those modes just now used the job transfer mode
剛剛那些模式都是用轉職模式
you inject cancer cells into
你將癌細胞注射進去
Then this is to let the mice produce cancer cells by themselves
那這個的話是讓老鼠自己去產生癌細胞
a bit closer to human
比較更接近人類一點
That's breast cancer
那這個是乳癌的
In this model, there are fifteen pairs of mice in Lu County, and ten
這個模式喔,老鼠有十五對魯縣,十個
That is in Lu County, so there are only ten in this place
那個魯縣,所以這個原位就十個
Then he will transfer to waste
那他會轉移到廢
About four months will be transferred to waste
大概四個月會轉移到廢
Then this is related to waste
那這個是廢來相關的
There are still a lot of finalists, ranking second in the world
入圍還是非常多的,在全世界是第二位
Then Taiwan is the fourth place, so this is no treatment
那台灣是第四位,那這個就是沒有治療
Radiation plus immunotherapy, this PDL1 antibody
放射加免疫治療,這PDL1的抗體
Immunotherapy is not the only one
那免疫治療其實不是只有一種
In our development rate of more than one hundred years, a very wide variety of immunotherapies have been developed
我們的那一百多年的發展率,有非常各式各樣不同的免疫治療被發展出來
Antibodies against PDL1 are one type of immunotherapy
PDL1的抗體就是其中一種免疫治療
Then our laboratory uses this cytokine immunotherapy
那我們實驗室是用這種細胞激素的免疫治療
Then this laboratory compares these two immunotherapies
那這個實驗室比較這兩種免疫治療
Effects of Concomitant Radiation Therapy
跟合併放射治療的效果
Just relying on immunotherapy, in the Jiangdong mode, there is no obvious effect
光是靠免疫治療,在降東模式是看不到太明顯的效果
But then combining those two treatments, it's pretty obvious
但是那合併這兩種治療,非常明顯的
The metastases to the lungs are also seen to be very obvious
對肺的轉移,也看到非常明顯
The white ones are metastatic cells
這個白色的就是轉移的細胞
Of course, these are still in animal experiment mode.
當然這些目前都還在動物實驗模式
We also recently communicated with National Taiwan University Animal Hospital
我們最近也跟台大動物醫院
Animals, dogs, cats, older, get cancer like that
動物,狗,貓,年紀大了,跟那一樣也會染上癌症
It also treats radiotherapy, chemotherapy, surgery
它治療也是這種放療、化療、手術
So the doctors at National Taiwan University Animal Hospital have been in contact with these patients
所以台大動物醫院的醫師就一直接觸到這些病人
We now hope that from small animals to a spontaneous pet cancer
我們現在就是希望能從小動物,到一個自發性的寵物的癌症
get closer to humans
跟人類又會更接近
Then, using this combination of radiation and immunization
然後,利用這種放射跟免疫的合併治療
This is our first therapy dog
這個就是我們第一個治療的狗
Received this radiation therapy at Taipei Medical University
在台北醫學大學接受這個放射治療
Then we'll give it immunotherapy
之後我們再給它做免疫治療
Then I took it to the National Taiwan University Animal Hospital for observation.
然後就帶到台大動物醫院去觀察
Finally, this history will make a summary
最後這張史來就做一個總結
It is hoped that immunotherapy will be combined with precise treatment
希望免疫治療合併精準的治療
or can eradicate cancer
或者可以消滅癌症
or you can coexist peacefully
或者你可以和平共存
long-term peaceful coexistence
長期的和平共存
this is also a cure
這樣也算是治癒
Then I think I will introduce you to this side today
那我想我今天就跟大家介紹到這邊
Then use half an hour
接下來就利用半小時的時間
Welcome to ask questions
歡迎大家提出問題
Well, we thank Teacher Cao Mihua for a very wonderful speech
好 我們謝謝曹米花老師非常精采的演講
let's open first
我們先就開放
please ask us
請把我們發問
Before I do that, let me announce
這之前我先宣布一下
we have prepared scientific magazine
我們有準備科學人雜誌
event book
有事本
So I encourage you to ask questions
所以鼓勵大家的發問
so we
所以我們
The first ten of us who asked the question
我們前面十個發問的
We'll have someone give one to a Science Man magazine
我們會有人給一個給一本科學人雜誌
good
好
Levi
李維
ask the professor
請教教授
just mentioned that
剛剛提到說那個
that immune system
那個免疫系統
And that T cell
還有那個T細胞
That good effect on our body
對我們身體的那個很好的作用
then i was thinking
那我在想
Prevention is better than cure
這個預防比治療重要
Then ask the professor how to live
那請問教授要怎麼樣的生活
how to take care of your body
怎麼樣的照顧身體
T cells can be stored in the body
可以讓體內存有T細胞
and have a good immune system
那還有有好的免疫系統
Thanks
謝謝
T cells have always been there
T細胞其實一直都存在
how to make it more
要怎麼樣讓它能夠多一點
In fact, this question is actually
其實這個問題其實
What level do you want to answer
你看要從什麼層面去回答
In fact, it is the traditional way that doctors tell you
其實就是現在傳統上醫生跟妳講的
Mom and Dad tell you about this healthy lifestyle
爸爸媽媽跟妳講的這種健康的生活方式
really say that
真會這樣講
Because Icene actually
因為Icene其實
she doesn't look like
她不像
Our general concept of vaccines is that you have a very clear enemy
我們一般疫苗概念就是你有一個很清楚的敵人
e.g. hepatitis B virus
比如說B肝病毒
you know what its antigen is
你知道它抗原是什麼
Then I will use this antigen in advance
那我就事先用這個抗原
to elicit an immune response
去引發出一個免疫反應
But cancer didn't happen before
可是癌症它沒有發生之前
you don't even know where
你根本不曉得在哪裡
even with cancer
即使產生癌症
The location of its mutation is also different
它的那個突變的位置也都不一樣
everyone may not know
每個人可能都不知道
also breast cancer
同樣是乳癌
But it has a neoantigen
可是它發生了新抗原
Because there are antigens
因為有antigen
Now think every patient may be different
現在認為每個病人可能都不一樣
So it's not like there's a cancer vaccine
所以不會說有一種癌症疫苗
Everyone will basically not
大家同時基本上不會
Rather, it may be that this precision
而是可能就是這種精準制
for this patient
針對這個病人
We need to find its tumor antigen
我們需要去找到它的腫瘤抗原
and then target this tumor antigen
然後再針對這個腫瘤抗原
to create this effective immune response
去製造這個有效的免疫的反應
Fortunately we are now
幸好我們現在這種
This software called Generational Genome Analysis
這種叫做世世代的基因體分析的軟體
very progress
非常的進步
so estimate
所以估計
Future cancer patients their cancer cells
未來癌症病人他們的癌細胞
do this again
再去做這種
sequencing of sequences
序列的定序
Yes, the price can be very high
可以 價格上面可以很
competitive
具有競爭力
I don't know how expensive it is
我現在還不太知道多貴
But it should get cheaper
可是應該會越來越便宜
Then it's possible to find
然後之後就有可能可以去找到
this patient
這一個病人
The position of his mutation gene mutation
他的mutature基因突變的位置
Then design according to this
然後呢 根據這個去設計
The best immunotherapy for this patient
最適合這個病人的免疫治療
As for how to go
那至於說怎麼樣去
to take care of cancer patients
去去照顧的癌細
that your good immunity
那個你的好的免疫
maintain a healthy life
大概就維持一個健康的生活狀態
Early to bed, early to rise, no drinking, no smoking
早睡早起 不要喝酒 不要抽菸
these sports
這些運動
these are very basic
這些很基本的
take care of some of the health
照顧健康的一些
deliberate act
有意的行為
So as long as there is
所以只要體內有
enough that
足夠的那個
Somatic cells and the good immune system
體細胞跟那個好的免疫系統
then
那就
It should definitely not be Nia.
應該就絕對不會尼亞了嘛
no
不會喔
I just said that
剛剛我講過就是說
That cancer cell is actually
那個癌細胞其實
have always existed
都一直存在
Then you T cells to kill him
然後你T cells去殺他的
Of course it will happen
那當然要發作啊
no way
沒有辦法
Because we have been exposed to these natural things
因為我們一直在接觸到這些自來物啊
Then our cells are in the process of replicating
然後我們的細胞在複製的過程
Our cells are always growing
我們細胞一直在生長
The growing process always goes wrong
生長過程總是會出錯
So there will always be errors in the process of copying
所以在複製的過程總是會出錯
Although the number is low, it adds up to a lot
雖然數目低可是累積起來就很多了
So there's almost no way you can say you're replicating cells
所以你幾乎沒有辦法說你在複細胞複製
assuming it's 100 percent correct
假設它百分之一百正確
there would be no cancer so to speak
就不會有癌症可以這麼講
But that is to say, there is no such thing as 100%
可是就是說沒有這種百分之一百的事
That is to say, our copy is in the process
就是說我們那個複製在過程裡面
some mutations will occur
都會發生一些突變
not so accurate
沒那麼準確
where some mutations occur
那有些發生突變的位置
components of cancer cells
就會造成癌細胞的成分
then some of us will attack him
那我們有些人會攻擊他
But cancer cells have been evolving, evolving, evolving
可是癌細胞他一直在演化演化演化演化
In the end he is not afraid of you
最後他就不怕你了
So I just talked about cancer
所以我剛才講癌症
The Four Survival Theory is just that
四者生存的理論就是這樣
So you can't say you have normal public opinion
所以不能說你有正常的民意性
you won't have cancer cells
你就不會有癌細胞
Because now cancer cells probably
因為現在癌細胞大概
Cancer counts in about five people
癌症大概統計五個人裡面
There's probably one of four or five people inside
大概有一個四到五個人裡面
So he's great
所以就是他很厲害
The enemies you have to deal with are powerful
你要對付的敵人很厲害
there is one over there
那邊有一位
right
對
please
請
teacher ask
老師請教一下
Just now the teacher talked about the base part
剛剛老師有講到那個基數的部分
Does that mean people with immune diseases
那是不是說有免疫疾病的人
less likely to get cancer
不容易得到癌症
Let's say you have erythroid cystic bowel
譬如說你有紅脈性囊腸
less likely to get breast cancer
比較不容易得到乳癌
This is a question with two sides
這是一題兩面
I think your question is like a scientist
我覺得你這個像是科學家的問題
right
對
You don't know what you're doing
你不曉得你是從事
Actually because
其實因為
cancer
癌症
I'm really not sure
我真的比較不確定
Have read the literature on this
有看過這方面的文獻
But I'm doing hepatitis virus myself
但是我自己在做肝炎病毒
he really did report
他真的是有這樣報告
some immune patients
一些肢體免疫的病人
Hepatitis Virus
比較不容易得悉性肝炎病毒
In fact, body immunity
其實肢體免疫
He's more of an overactive immune system
他就比較過度活化的這些免疫系統
then it looks like
然後看起來
for some infectious diseases
對一些感染性疾病
that's right
是這樣沒錯
chronic infectious disease
慢性的感染性疾病
So I think it's possible
所以我覺得這個是有可能的
but i'm not sure
但是我不確定
has anyone done it
有沒有人去做過
one like this
像這樣子的一個
A large-scale statistical analysis
一個大規模的統計分析
I think this is in public health
我想這個在公衛
This is a possible research topic
這個是一個可以進行的研究題目
font immune patient
字體免疫的病人
is it his cancer
是不是他的癌症
or certain cancers
或者某一些特別的癌症
The attack rate will be lower
的罹患率會比較低一些
I think it is theoretically possible
我覺得理論上是有可能
I just had two questions over there.
我剛那邊有兩位要發問的
Did it just come here?
這邊剛有嗎
OK, so is it?
好 那有也是嗎
thank you
那謝謝
one thing yes please
有一點 是的 請你
Interesting Topics for Chinese Speech
中式發言有趣的議題
What I want to ask is that it is mentioned that
想要請問的是有提到說
is the total number of T cells
就是T細胞的總數
affect the effectiveness of the entire treatment
會影響整個治療的療效
The total number of T cells
那這個T細胞總數
different types of T cells
是各種不同類型的T細胞
Or it is said that it is Satutoxic T cell
或者是有說它是Satutoxic T cell
Or Suppressor T cell
或者是Suppressor T cell
Regulatory T cell
Regulatory T cell
Is there any Specific T cell?
有任何Specific T cell嗎
or total
還是是總數
ok then back to this
好 那回到這位
I may have just misdefined
我可能剛剛沒有界定清楚
T cell hormone is the T cell hormone in the seed stream
T細胞種素是種流裡面的T細胞種素
in the blood that doesn't count
血液裡面那不算
In the blood, don't you only deal with the blood?
血液裡面你看你不是只對付種流嘛
You still have to deal with these dimensional creatures, these creatures
你還要對付這些維生物啊這些生物
So our body's T cells are not just to deal with the flow
所以我們身體的T細胞不是只來對付種流的
Then the T cell hormones we are talking about are
那我們講的T細胞種素就是說
T cell seed
種流裡面的T細胞種素
Because this T cell will go to the seed stream
因為這T細胞會跑到種流
It is probably the flow of knowledge
它大概就是認識種流
So what kind of T cells are more effective?
所以那另外就是T細胞什麼樣類型的T細胞比較有效
Because T cells have a type called
因為T細胞有一種叫做
You just mentioned that they are heterozygous T cells
你剛剛有提過就是異字型T細胞
Regulate T cells this is bad
Regulate T細胞這個是不好的
So there is Correlation
所以有Correlation
If we say that there are many different types of T cells
如果說這種異字型T細胞多
In fact, the prognosis for it is relatively bad.
其實對它預後比較不好
Icva is afraid of Cd8 T cells
那Icva怕的是Cd8的T細胞
So it should be more and more Cd8T cells
所以應該是Cd8T細胞越數目越多
its prognosis
那它的預後
Overall prognosis will be better
Overall的預後會比較好
that gentleman
那位先生
professor please
教授請問一下
That's because there is a Dr. Zhuang
那個因為有一個莊博士也
The last issue was to coexist with cancer
曾經最後它的那個議題是以癌共存
It's after the invention of that towel fuck
它就是發明那個毛巾操之後
Use that energy to be in touch with the heavens and the earth to coexist with cancer
利用那個跟天地接觸那些能量來以癌共存
That is to say
那這樣的話就是說
Will its activity just increase that kind of
它這種活動會不會就是增加那種
increased immune system
就免疫系統的增加
In this case, if we promote everyone to exercise
這樣的話如果推行大家都運動的話
It is less likely to say that cancer arises
它比較不會說癌症就產生出來
Do you have any research on this?
你們會不會有這方面的研究
Ladies and gentlemen, I can only talk about a healthy lifestyle.
各位長我只能講說健康的生活形態
What you said just now should actually be a kind of exercise.
你剛才講這種其實應該就是一種運動
When you exercise as a whole, it is more important to your overall physical condition
你運動在整體就對你的整個的身體狀況是比較
The whole of this includes the immune system
就整個的這個包括在免疫系統
It should be healthier
應該就是會比較健康一點
But is it because of this that you don't get cancer?
但是是不是因為這樣子就不得癌症
This is difficult to go, it should be in nature
這個很難去應該就是在自然在
In science, no correlation like this has been studied
在科學上面,沒有像這樣子的關聯性被研究出來
Some people you can see some people you can see in the packing yard
有些人,你可以看到,有些人在包裝場可以看到
Life is very healthy now, long-distance running, triathlon, non-smoking
生活現在非常健康,長跑的,三鐵的,不抽菸的
This is the proof
這樣就來證了
So that is to say, because IC8 appeared in the evolution process
所以就是說,因為IC8它就是在演化過程裡面出現的
Sometimes your physical condition does not mean that you are immune
有時候你身體狀況其實不代表你免疫的能力強
So this part is hard to talk about
所以這部分就很難去講
But, overall, as long as you maintain a healthy lifestyle
但是,總體而言,你只要維持健康的生活型態
must be helpful
一定是有幫忙的
For example, some cancer-causing factors are known, such as obesity
比如說,有一些致癌的因子是知道,比如說肥胖
This inflammatory response, these are all bad
這個發炎反應,這些都是不好的
this is a danger signal
這個是危險的訊號
So if you say that the factors that can reduce the risk of these cancers
所以你如果說能夠降低這些致癌的危險的因子
Then your overall VL ratio will drop, this is known
那整體的你的VL比率會下,這個是知道的
For example, like our carriers of hepatitis B virus
比如說像我們得B型肝炎病毒的帶原者
If you can take medicine to control the number of hepatitis B virus
你如果能夠服藥去控制B型肝炎病毒的數目
that will reduce
那就會減少
At least you get liver cancer rates
至少你得到肝癌发生率
know this
这个是知道的
there are two over there i think
那边有两位我想
Mr. Levi that
李维先生那个
Hello Professor
教授你好
The question I want to ask is to say
我想提的问题是说
It was mentioned just now, in fact, it was mentioned at the beginning
刚刚有提到其实一开始提到
our immune system
我们的免疫系统
In fact, there are many different types of immune cells
其实有很多种不同的免疫性的细胞
Contains GCC cells B cells and T cells
包含GCC胞B细胞跟T细胞
Today's is what the professor just mentioned
那今天的就是教授刚刚提到的
The main part of immunotherapy
主要的免疫治疗的部分
The feeling is to focus on the part of T cells
感觉就是着重在T细胞的部分
Then in immunotherapy
那请问在免疫治疗里面
Does it target B cells
是否有针对于B细胞
Or related functions of GCC cells
或者是GCC胞的相关的功能
other research done
所做出来的其他的研究
Thanks
谢谢
That is, the immune system, in addition to T cells
那就是免疫系统除了T细胞之外
Are other cells
其他细胞是不是
T cells do not activate themselves
T细胞它不会自己活化
right
对不对
It requires antigen presenting cells
它需要抗原呈现的细胞
it will be alive
它才会活活
so the immune system it's not
所以免疫系统它不是
can exist independently
就可以单独独立存在
It's actually B cells that have a very tight
它其实B细胞有非常紧密的
regulatory relationship
调控的关系
The function of B cells
那B细胞它的功能
Antibodies
主要是承证抗体
Antibody
抗体
We now especially synthetically affirm
我們現在尤其是綜合性肯定
for microbial vaccines
它對微生物疫苗來講
it plays a big part
它扮演很大的角色
this microbe
就是這個微生物
It would have been by invading the cells of the body
它本來會藉由侵犯人體的細胞
into this cell
進入這個細胞裡面
Then achieve the purpose of infection
然後達到感染的目的
Then if there are antibodies
那如果有抗體的話
synthesize it
綜合它
That virus can't get in
那那病毒進不去
But the antibody has to go directly
可是抗體要直接去
It also does not directly kill cancer cells
它也不會直接殺死癌細胞
What it does is probably
它的作用大概就是
It binds cancer cells by
它可以藉由結合癌細胞
then deactivate
然後去活化
For example, NK cells
比如說NK細胞
activate the phagocytic cells
活化剛剛講這個吞噬細胞
is possible by means of something like this
是有可能藉由像這樣子的方式
to achieve the effect of cancer control
去達到控制癌症的效果
But at least for now
但是目前至少目前知道
That is to say, in this whole cancer immunotherapy
就是說在這個整個癌症免疫治療的
In the current experience like this
這樣子的目前的經驗裡面
The role of T cells
T細胞扮演的角色
cellular immunity
更早就是細胞性免疫
more important role
扮演的角色更重要
from animal experiments
從動物實驗
Follow the end of these cancer diseases in humans
跟從人類的這些癌症病的結尾
looks like this
看起來像是這樣
So now immunotherapy
所以現在免疫治療
In fact, the general research focus is on
其實大概的研究的重點是放在
How to strengthen the patient's
怎麼樣加強這個病人的
professional system fort
專業性的體系堡
That must be my fault
那必須我不能講錯
it's useless
它沒用
but relatively speaking
而是說相對的來講
Your role may be more prominent in the system
體系堡辦你的作用可能更突出
that lady is in front
那小姐在前面
right
對
Hello, teacher
老師您好
I just heard more
剛剛聽到比較多的是
Related to immuno checkpoint
跟immuno checkpoint相關的
For example, for CARTE
那譬如說針對CARTE的話
technology like this
像這樣子的技術
Is it still in clinical trials
它是還在臨床實驗嗎
or already in some countries
還是已經在有些國家是
can be used to execute
可以用來執行
already on sale
已經在賣囉
That Novatis
那個Novatis
should
應該
This is already listed
這已經是上市的
This is the product that can be bought
就是這個產品是可以買
But something like this
但是像這樣子的東西
Every patient has to do its own CARTE sales
每個病人要做它自己的CARTE sales
So the second question I want to ask is to say
所以第二個問題我想要請教的是說
So if we want to treat with CARTE
那這樣子如果我們要用CARTE治療的話
how long will it take
大概要花多久的時間
will be wrong
才會有錯
enough T cells
足夠的T細胞
Is it possible that this T cell came from a
那這個T細胞有沒有可能是從像
extreme blood or other
極代血或其他的
is used
是用
STEM cell and then go to Differentiate to enough T cell
STEM cell然後去Differentiate到足夠的T cell
If you hit someone's body, you must still
再打到人的身體還是一定要在
Should be difficult from STEM cell
應該從STEM cell很困難
Because the STEM cell just mentioned is the one
因為剛剛講STEM cell就是那個
hematopoietic cells
造血母細胞
it differentiates a lot
它分化要分化很多
You want to divide it has a mature T cell
你要分它有一個成熟的T細胞
It's not easy
其實不太容易
So usually the patient's own
所以通常是用病人自己的
mature T cells
已經成熟的T細胞
remodel it
再去改造它
But if I've found out that I have cancer
可是如果我已經發現說我有癌症了
Then I still have time to go
那這樣我還有時間去
Store enough T cells
儲存足夠的T細胞
Do you want to do the next Carty?
去做之後的Carty嗎
or i might
還是我可能
for example
譬如說
How much is best to have every year
每年最好要有多少的
enough stock
存量去足夠
Will be a Carty cell in the future
日後做Carty cell
there is no way to do it like
沒有辦法像這樣做
usually i
通常我
Because of Carty cell
因為Carty cell
I didn't say it myself
我自己不是說
Because I am a mouse myself
因為我自己是做老鼠的
so many are
所以很多都是
purple ice pop
紫上彈冰
But you'll be exposed to information like this
但是就是會接觸到一些像這樣的資訊
Cartysales me
Cartysales 我
I
我
I ran into a graduate student from our biomedical institute about a few weeks ago
我大概前幾個禮拜碰到我們生醫所過去的一個研究生
Then he is in this company now
那他現在就是在這公司
So called Cartysales
所以叫Cartysales
Then I had a lot of ideas in the past
那我本來有很多觀念我過去
I thought it was okay to ask this lady if it was done
我本來以為說這個做起來可不可以跟這位女士問的問題
may take a long time
可能要滿久的
But they are in that company now
可是他們現在在那公司
He told me about two to three weeks
他跟我講大概兩個禮拜到三個禮拜
They can make this patient's Cartysales
他們可以做出這個病人的Cartysales
he's so handsome
他這樣子都非常可觀
That is to say, it is actually very competitive.
就是說這樣子其實就非常具有競爭力
But there is still no way to solve the problem that is
但是還是沒有辦法解決問題就是說
Every patient has to do his own Cartysales
每一個病人都要做專屬於他自己的Cartysales
How to prepare this Cartysales
那這Cartysales怎麼樣去自備
how to deactivate
怎麼樣去活化
Then how to save
然後怎麼樣去存化
These will be some of the challenges in manufacturing
這些都會是製造上面的一些挑戰
then you can imagine
然後你可以想像
His price will be higher than the one I just put on
他的價錢會比我剛剛就剛剛在放的那個要
more, because after that drug was made
更多,因為那種藥物是做出來之後
Everyone can use it, every cancer patient can
每個人都可以用,每個癌症病人都可以
The first time you see it, only you can use it
你看到第一次,只有你自己可以用
There are four prices, I believe it will not be cheap
有四價錢我相信一定不會便宜
so if i already have cancer
所以如果我已經有癌症的話
can i still have time
我還來得及? 是,現在看起來是
Now the most effective treatment is for blood cancer patients.
那現在最有效的就是血癌的病人
If you get a blood cancer patient
如果你得到是個血癌的病人
Especially a species called CD19
尤其是種叫CD19
related B cell blood cancer
相關的B細胞的血癌
The cure rate is very high
那治癒率非常的高
here, this bit, yes
這裡,這個位,對
Then sit in the back seat over there
然後那邊坐後面的位
come here first
先到這邊
hello professor, thank you for your presentation
教授您好,謝謝您的演講
I have two questions, the first one is
我是有兩個問題,第一個問題是
According to T-cell receptor
根據T-cell receptor
It is in Encode T-cell receptor
它在Encode T-cell receptor
Is to use VDGA recombination
是用VDGA recombination
so fearadically the repertoire
所以fearadically the repertoire
of the T-cell detection would be
of the T-cell detection would be
If you can detect different energies, there will be a lot of people playing
如果你可以去偵測不同的能量,那會有很多人打
Is there any related research to find out which T-cell in your body can contain Detect Cancer like Service Market
有沒有相關的研究是去找出你身體內哪一個T-cell可以含有Detect Cancer的那個像Service Market
The total rate of T-cell is very high, it is generated by this Recombination
T-cell總率非常多,它是藉由這個Recombination產生的
It recognizes a lot of antigens, so you just know its sequence is useless
它辨識的抗原非常多,所以你光是知道它Sequence其實是沒有用的
You know its Sequence, but you don’t actually know what this T-cell knows.
你知道它Sequence,可是你其實並不曉得說這個T-cell到底是認識什麼東西
So now it's the other way around, you first find its mutation
所以現在是反過來,你先去找到它的Mutation
Because T-cell recognition is these Mutation Antigen
因為T-cell認識就是這些Mutation Antigen
Then you use the so-called Neo Antigen of this Mutation
然後你再用這個Mutation的這個所謂的現在叫Neo Antigen
Go see if you can stimulate the concept of T-cell, assuming that this Neo Antigen can stimulate the patient's T-cell
去看看能不能去刺激T-cell的概念,假設這個Neo Antigen可以刺激病人的T-cell
It is resistance, copy, and then see the sequence of a certain group of system packages, T-cell receptor, it really increases, then you know that this T-cell should know this neo-antigen, but the other way around
是抗性,複製,然後看到某一群的體系包的 sequence, T-cell receptor,真的就增加了,那你就知道說這個 T-cell應該是認識這一個 neo-antigen,可是反過來講
Another question is that your laboratory has research on combination of therapies, first you use the radiation to induce destruction of determining microenvironment, and then followed by introduction of T-cells,
還有一個問題,就是您的實驗室有 research on combination of therapies, first you use the radiation to induce destruction of determining microenvironment, and then followed by introduction of T-cells,
You can talk to us on camera, I can't hear you
你可以講給我們拍機,我聽不到
OK, so this question is to say, as I just said,
好,所以這個問題就是說,剛剛講過,
For example, tumors are afraid of T-cell
比如說腫瘤怕T-cell
It's good if there are T-cells in the tumor recently
如果最近腫瘤裡面有T-cell那很好
Because yours may be more responsive
因為你那個可能比較有反應
So the problem just now is that my lab is doing
所以剛剛問題是我實驗室在做的
radiation therapy first
先做放射線治療
followed by immunotherapy
然後再用免疫治療
After radiation therapy
放射線治療照下去之後
The T-cells in the tumor were killed
腫瘤裡面的T-cell被殺掉了
that's right
確實是沒錯
But where does the T-cell come from?
但是T-cell到底後面是哪來的
come on those questions
來,那些問題
Where is the T-cell confirmed?
Where is the T-cell confirmed?
do not forget
不要忘記
It's our body's immune system
就是我們身體的免疫系統
in the bone marrow
在骨髓
bone marrow modeling blast
骨髓有造型母細胞
It keeps making T-cell out
它一直在製造T-cell出來
only when there is a tumor
只是有腫瘤的時候
As soon as your T-cell is attracted to the tumor
你這T-cell一被吸引到腫瘤
It becomes an inhibitory T-cell
它就變成抑制型的T-cell
it loses function
它就失去功能
Then if we use radiation
那我們如果藉由放射線
destroy it this tumor for the environment
破壞它這個腫瘤為環境
destroy its inhibiting environment
破壞它這個抑制的環境
break down its fortress
打破它的堡壘
In this way, you are in the newly generated T-cell
這樣的話你在新產生的T-cell
it has a chance
它就有機會
will generate a
會產生一個
effective aggressive
有效的具有攻擊性的
A functional system is packaged out
具有功能的體系包出來
It's all about our principles
這是我們所有的原理
that is
就是說
It's like breaking cancer into chains
等於是把癌症打掉成鏈
Use the square ray to knock it out first
先用方射線把它打掉
After destroying its entire environment
打掉之後它整個環境
becomes an inflamed environment
就變成一個類似發炎的環境
At this time it is beneficial
這個時候它有利於
immune response
免疫反應的發生
immune response triggered like bacteria
像細菌一樣引發的免疫反應
Because if cancer is like bacteria
因為如果說癌症像細菌
to elicit such a strong immune response
要引發那麼強的免疫反應
Then we probably won't be afraid of cancer
那我們大概不會怕癌症
It is mostly after cancer cells
它最主要是癌細胞後
It's too much like we can system package
它太像我們能體系包
less likely to produce a severe inflammation
就不太會產生一個嚴重的發炎
So you try it out on a T-shirt
所以你試試它出來的T-Shirt
less functional
就不太有功能
But our T-shirt has always existed
但是我們T-Shirt一直都存在
You know it takes care of your immune type
你知道它要顧好你免疫型
The soundness of hematopoietic organs
造血器官的健全
you will always provide these
你會一直在提供這些
Normal T-Shirt comes out
正常的T-Shirt出來
Mr. Mina
Mina先生
Hello, Professor, I am Jianfu
教授你好我是建復
I'm glad you went deep into the future and talked about it in such detail.
很高興你深入前途講這麼詳細
Molecular In-Depth Physician
分子深入的醫師
also our teacher
也是我們的老師
I think the professor just mentioned that
我想就是教授剛剛有提到說
Play that BDL at the beginning
一開始放那個BDL
There is MuseoField going to eat bacteria
有MuseoField要去吃細菌
but he
可是他
He will have MuseoField
他會有MuseoField
but he should be
但是他應該是
because he is doing cancer
因為他在做癌症
he has been providing
他一直在提供
MuseoField
MuseoField
In the whole process, the structure of the RVC next to it also becomes Cancel sale
它在整個過程裡面 旁邊的RVC 它的結構也變成Cancel sale
Even red blood cells that become polar cells start to change in shape
就是變成極狀細胞的紅血球 它外型也開始改變
It's in the process of chasing some of our MACO jurisprudence or some
它在追逐過程中 我們的一些MACO法學或一些
Will the lost fee release some H2O2 to chase
迷路費用會釋出一些H2O2去追逐嗎
Or an RVC change that caused its modulus
還是說造成它的模的一個RVC的變化
Then after this change in the RVC of the polar cell it becomes like that
那在這個變化的極細胞的RVC 它變成那個樣子之後
Does the blood flow that helps us maintain our blood vessels become slower
是不是有助於我們維持血管的血流變得更慢
But some MACO jurisprudence has a chance to get where it wants to go
但一些MACO法學有機會進入到它想到達的地方
Because the velocity can be slower
因為流速可以比較慢
Is that in turn a chance for us
那是不是反過來有機會我們
Like the teacher you just mentioned a good model
像剛剛老師您提到一個很好的model
It's after Redaction, which stimulates immunity to the storm
就是Redaction它刺激了免疫風暴之後
make that place a structure
把那個地方做一個結構
Attract other new TC packs
吸引其他新的TC包過來
Then we will evaluate it later
那我們以後要評估它的
Check whether the treatment or operating treatment is effective
在看治療或是營運的治療有沒有效
Do we have a chance to look at local nearby RBC cells
我們是不是有機會看局部附近的RBC細胞
Originally the plane of Guanghua's outer sphere
原本是光華的外球的平面
It has become some acute cells or extremely strong protrusions
它已經變成是一些急細胞或極壯突起的
Its proportions can also become a pathological one
它的比例也可以成為一個病理的一個
A reference to the early stages of an effective response
有效反應的初期的一個參考
Thanks
謝謝
Thank you for your careful observation
謝謝你這麼細心的觀察
In fact, I played this video for so long
其實我這影片放那麼久
I never went to see that RBC
我從來沒有去看那個RBC
Is there something you just said about the RBC shape change and so on
是不是有你剛剛講過說RBC形狀改變等等
I just said I really didn't pay attention
我剛剛說我真的沒有注意看
Because this is from a published magazine
因為這個就是從一個發表雜誌裡面
to expose it
去把它揭露下來的
the object of its study
它研究的對象
It's what I just said, it sees bacteria
就是我剛剛講的它看到就是細菌
See the neutral white blood cells in this city
看到就是這個市中性的白血球
A lot of these optical things sometimes suffer a bit
很多這些光學的東西有時候會受到一些影響
But I guess it whole research doesn't mention this RBC
但是我想它整個研究並沒有提到這個RBC
to know me
要對我所知
What about RBC? I can't say it has no impact.
RBC呢 不能講說沒有影響
Because many scientists are more conservative
因為很多科學家都會比較保守一些
If you don't know, just say you don't know
你不曉得你就說不曉得
So RBC did not say that it is in immunotherapy
所以RBC並沒有說在免疫治療裡面
Now I know what kind of role to play
現在知道說扮演什麼樣的角色
currently no
目前是沒有
As for whether he will affect immunotherapy
至於說他會不會影響到免疫治療
He can also know by being a medium
他透過當作一個媒體也可以知道
The effect of immunotherapy
免疫治療的效果
There is no such related report either
也沒有這種相關的報告
Because basically the peritch compound H2O2
因為基本上過癢化物H2O2
After getting around by our MACOFARG or MUCOFIL
被我們MACOFARG或MUCOFIL四處之後
Maybe to our RBC's CELL MEMBER
也許對我們的RBC的CELL MEMBER
will cause a change in the structure
會造成結構上的一個變化
so maybe it will be a reference
所以也許會是一個參考指標
That is to say, if like MUCOFIL, MACOFIL
就是說如果像MUCOFIL、MACOFIL
These phagocytes
這些吞噬細胞
The principle of its activation is as you just mentioned
它活化的原理就像你剛才提到的
perpruritics or some other
過癢化物或其他的一些
Like NL, this is called heterooxidized egg
像NL這個叫異氧化蛋
or other principles of these bactericidal phagocytes
或其他的這些吞噬細胞的殺菌的原理
may cause damage to some organizations
都有可能會造成一些組織的破壞
So where we are speaking
所以我們在發言的部位
In fact, some tissue damage will be seen
其實會看到一些組織的受傷
need to fix later
之後需要去修補
It was also mentioned that
那這些也有人提到說
These are likely to
這些有可能對
Cancer cells have a similar ability to attack
癌細胞也有類似的攻擊能力
But this role he plays is complicated
但是這個他辦的角色很複雜
Because you just saw his immunotherapy cells
因為你剛剛看到他的免疫治細胞
Many of these phagocytes
很多都是這些吞噬細胞
He called this phagocyte
他把這吞噬細胞叫過去
cancer cells called him
癌細胞把他叫過來
All his beliefs became his
全部都把他信念成他的
that
那個
defense force
防衛隊
So he is helping the cancer cells
所以他到底他是幫忙癌細胞
It's more active now
還是現在比較多人動的說
Those inside those cancer cells
那一些癌細胞裡面的這些
phagocyte
吞噬細胞
We no longer call him Phagocyte
我們這時候已經不叫他吞噬細胞
we are called
我們叫做
Immunotherapy
免疫治細胞
Most of his roles are to help cancer cells
他辦的角色比較多是幫忙癌細胞
instead of killing cancer cells
而不是去殺癌細胞
More evidence now
現在比較多證據
But there are also special reports that say
但是也有一些特別報告顯示說
He also seems to have the ability to kill cancer cells
他好像也有殺癌細胞的能力
thank you very much thank you
很感謝你謝謝
in the middle
中間有
right
對
we usually say
我們平常說
You shouldn't be sick if you eat all you can
不該不盡吃了沒病
that is our immune cells
那就是我們的免疫細胞
The system is affected by some TRIGGER
系統受到一些TRIGGER
So the immune system is getting stronger
所以免疫系統越來越強
That Uncertain this natural thing
那個Uncertain這個自來物
is it possible for him
他有沒有可能
That is, we are all afraid of things that come from us.
就是我們都很怕自來物
But is it possible for him
可是他有沒有可能
On the contrary, it will strengthen
反而會去強化
our immune system
我們的這個免疫的一個系統
under certain critical conditions
就是在某一些關鍵的狀況之下
Then there is another question, that is
那還有另外一個問題就是說
It was mentioned at the beginning
最開始的時候有提到
severe inflammatory reaction
嚴重的發炎反應
last cancer cell
最後癌細胞
Severe cancer cells are eliminated
嚴重的癌細胞就消除了
But now there is more and more evidence that
可是現在也越來越多證據說
Inflammation is linked to many cancers
發炎反應是跟很多癌症有關的
So this severe inflammation is
所以這一個嚴重的發炎是
On the contrary, it can miraculously cure cancer
反而可以奇蹟式的治癒癌症
that in chronic inflammation
那在慢性的發炎
On the contrary, it is related to many cancers
反而是跟很多癌症有關
So what is the rationale for this?
那請問這個這樣的道理是怎麼樣
explain it
解釋它
basically two questions
基本上兩個問題
One is what trains cancer
一個就是什麼訓練癌症
Cancer is not liver or tendon
癌症不肝不腱
In fact, not liver or tendon
其實不肝不腱
Probably Vitality
大概就是維生物
So in our physical environment
所以我們身體環境裡面
training with what you eat
你吃到的東西訓練
Now there are a lot of beauties who have problems
那現在有一個非常多的美人就有課題
Bacteriology, that is, our human body
菌象學,就是說我們人體
It's not just human cells
其實也不是只有人體細胞
If you look at the skin, look at the gut
你如果去看皮膚,看腸道
There's a lot of bacteria, a lot of microbes
有非常多的細菌,非常多的微生物
that some research is now very clear
那有一些研究現在已經非常清楚了
It's you who put the mouse
就是你把那個老鼠
kept in a sterile environment
養在一個無菌的環境
keep it free of bacteria
讓它全身都沒有細菌
This mouse's immune system is unhealthy
這種老鼠的免疫系統是不健康的
It was even found that
甚至有發現就是說
Cancer in these bacteria-free mice
這些沒有細菌的老鼠的cancer的癌症
Your immune system treatment is useless
你用免疫系治療是沒效的
So bacteria to some extent
所以細菌在某些程度
Humans need symbiotic bacteria with humans
人類需要跟人類的共生菌
This is called symbiotic bacteria
這叫共生菌
It promotes the development of your immune system
它能夠促進你免疫系統的發展
so this is there
所以這個是有的
But Uncogean these chemical carcinogens
但是Uncogean這些化學致癌物
Probably not the concept
大概就不是這個概念
Chemical carcinogens are these chemicals
化學致癌物就是這些化學物質
Its main working principle
它主要的作用原理
It's what triggers you to mutate
它是引發你在突變
Increase the mutation rate, such as UV radiation, chemical substances
增加突變率,比如說放UV照射,化學物質
The higher your mutation rate, the greater the chance of normal bubbles turning into bubbles
那你突變率越高,正常氣泡變成的氣泡機會就越大
So this has nothing to do with immunity, but it is the reason why Tumor generates the entire tumor bubble
所以這個跟免疫比較沒有關係,反而是tumor把整個腫瘤氣泡怎麼生成的原因
As for the second question, you can remind me again
那第二個問題,你可以再提醒我
It's a severe inflammatory reaction.
就是很嚴重的發炎反應
In fact, the inflammatory response is what we need, but chronic inflammation is not good
其實發炎反應我們那些是需要,但是慢性發炎是不好的
Then you just watched that Coli, I was thinking why people in the future can’t copy it
那你剛剛看那個Coli,我在想就是說為什麼我們以後的人都沒辦法複製
Because there's no way we're going to allow a hospital to feel so inflammatory.
因為我們根本不可能容許一個院內感到有這麼嚴重的發炎反應
Antibiotics knocked him out in the morning, because infection with inflammatory bacteria is serious
早上抗生素把他打掉,因為發炎細菌的感染是很嚴重的
You were fast then, and...
那當時你很快,而且...
So immediacy is gone
所以即性就沒了
Therefore, the current medical treatment cannot allow this kind of
所以現在的醫療不可能容許這種
The presence of an immediate bacterial infection such as
這樣子的一個即性的細菌感染的存在
that in the past
那在過去
In Coly100s
在Coly100年代
you have no choice
你沒有什麼選擇
no antibiotics at all
根本沒有抗生素
so you don't go to therapy
所以你不會去治療
So some patients will get serious infections
所以有些病人他就會很嚴重的感染
So like in a severe infection
那所以像在嚴重的感染
localized inflammation
在局部去產生發炎反應
Some patients may survive
有些病人可能就撐過去了
the cancer may be under control
那癌症可能就受到控制
However, some patients may have bacterial infections
可是有些病人可能細菌感染
cause fatal
就造成致命的原因
inflammatory reaction
那他發炎反應
Like chronic inflammation vs instant inflammation
好像慢性發炎跟即性發炎
It's a different concept
是不太一樣的概念
chronic inflammation such as obesity
慢性發炎比如肥胖
is a chronic inflammation
是一種慢性發炎
rhinohepatitis virus infection
鼻型肝炎病毒感染
It causes chronic inflammation of the liver
它會造成肝臟慢性發炎
chronic inflammation it will create this environment
慢性發炎它會製造這個環境
Let the death of this cell
讓這細胞的死亡率
Increased replication rate
複製率增加
In fact, it also increases its mutation rate
其實也是增加它的突變率
increase the chance of cancer cells
就增加它癌細胞產生的機會
So this one might be heavier
所以這個就是可能更沉
Some are to help IC package generation
有些是幫忙IC包產生
But the activation of young cells requires an inflammatory environment
但是年益細胞的活化需要一個發炎的環境
This is certain
這是確定
it's almost time
時間差不多到了
our last question
我們那個最後一個問題
The teacher asks a question
老師請教一個問題
Will total flow T cells have something to do with genetics?
總流T細胞會跟遺傳有關係嗎
Let's say the parents already have cancer
我們假設說父母已經得了癌症
Will the cultivation of his T cells be effective for his children?
他的T細胞的培養給子女會有沒有效
that is
就是
Thanks
謝謝
T cells cannot interact with each other
T細胞不能夠彼此
I just said that T cells can only use your own
剛剛講T細胞只能夠用你自己的
Why?
為什麼?
Because we humans probably know about organ rejection
因為我們人類大概知道器官的排斥
when you want to pass on your organs
你要遺持器官的時候
You have to match your tissue antigens first
你要先去配對你的組織抗原
Finding Rarely Becomes Finding Just Right
找到很少就變成可以找到正好
Otherwise there will be twins
要不然就有同軟雙生
His tissue antigens are the same
他的組織抗原都一樣
you can pass
你可以遺持
same concept
同樣的概念
That is to say, your T cells
就是說你T細胞
And who is that exclusion?
而且那個排斥是誰排斥
It's the T cells that are rejecting
就是T細胞在排斥
Because he went to meet a foreign
因為他去碰到一個外來的
something he doesn't know
他不認識的東西
He repells you and kills you
他就把你排斥掉 把你殺掉
So if you want to do TCL
所以呢 你如果要做TCL
unless your one
除非你的那個
of these tissue antigens
這些組織抗原的
ask you
跟你要
To give you TCL exactly the same
要給你TCL一模一樣
That's probably only possible with soft twins.
那大概同軟雙生的才有可能
the parents
那父母親的
Your mother can, but your parents'
你媽媽可以 可是你父母親的
To you, you're half dad
對你來講 你是一半爸爸
half mom, right?
一半媽媽 對不對
so you that
所以你那個
parents too
父母親的也是
also not
也是不行
usually you just
通常就是你就
Use your own TCL
就要用自己的TCL
to manufacture
去製造出來
to be able to use it on oneself
才能夠用在自己身上
So when we talked about Cartysail just now
所以剛剛講的Cartysail的時候
Or something like TIL
或者是TIL這種
T cell infusion therapy
T細胞輸入療法
from the patient's blood
就是要從病人的血液裡面
extract his T cells
抽取他的T細胞
a lot of cultivation
大量的培養
and inject it back into the patient
然後再注射回這個病人體內
That is, if
也就是說 如果是
The same soft twins have a chance
同軟雙胞胎 才有機會
Others have no chance, that's what it means
其他的就沒有機會 是這個意思
should be if you say you want
應該是 如果說你要
must use other people's words
一定要用別人的話
Now you can technically use your own TIL
現在可以 技術上你可以用到自己的TIL
But I think technical development is theoretically not impossible
但是我想技術上發展理論上不是不可能
Because you only need to say that the card you use is T cell
因為你只要就是說你用的卡T cell
Is it not showing these reasons
是不表現這些機因
These organizations just mentioned seem theoretically possible
這些剛剛講的組織看起來理論上是有可能
So I know that there are also people who are working on the card T cell
所以我知道也有人在研究卡T cell
Hope to make a universal T cell
希望能夠做出一個萬用型的T細胞
Only in this way can it be used more quickly in most patients
這樣的話才能夠更快的使用在大部分的病人身上
But these are still in the research stage
但是這些還是在研究的階段
ok i now our time is up
好 我現在我們的時間也到了
i know there are many questions
我知道還有很多問題
So maybe that Mr. Tao would like to stay a few minutes longer
所以也許那個陶老師願意多留幾分鐘
But I think we're officially here now
但是我想現在我們就正式就在這邊
that's where the speech ends
就是演講在這裡結束
I'll make one now
那我現在做一個
Teachers are next month's knowledge prize banquet
老師們就是下個月的知識獎宴
Is the director of Lin Ziyi's special evaluation researcher at the law firm
是在法律所的林子儀特評研究員間所長
The director of the law firm will conduct atomic and molecular research at the campus of National Taiwan University
法律所的所長會在台大校本部的原子與分子研究
Institute of Science Former Branch
科學研究所 原分所
All are welcome on September 26th
9月26號 歡迎大家參加
ok then thanks again
好 那麼再次感謝
Professor Tao Minhua
陶敏華教授
static performance static performance
靜態的表演 靜態的演出